<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications | Ian T. Adams</title>
    <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publications</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©`2021`</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 16:00:37 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ianadamsresearch.com/media/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandatory Sexual Assault Kit Testing Policies and Arrest Trends a Natural Experiment</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2021-01-11-mandatory-sexual-assault-kit-testing-policies-and-arrest-trends-a-natural-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 16:00:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2021-01-11-mandatory-sexual-assault-kit-testing-policies-and-arrest-trends-a-natural-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://smourtgos.netlify.app/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Scott M. Mourtgos&lt;/a&gt;, University of Utah&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ianadamsresearch.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ian T. Adams&lt;/a&gt;, University of Utah&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Justin Nix&lt;/a&gt;, University of Nebraska Omaha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=VZ_LDHQAAAAJ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tara Richards&lt;/a&gt;, University of Nebraska Omaha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Untested sexual assault kits (SAKs) represent a critical public policy gap in addressing sexual assault, with estimates suggesting that as many as 400,000 SAKs remain untested in police storage across the country (Office of the Press Secretary, 2015). Indeed, despite the evidentiary usefulness of SAKs (Valentine et al., 2019), large numbers of SAKs are ‘shelved’ and never submitted to crime laboratories for analysis (Campbell et al., 2015; Hendrix et al., 2019; Lovell et al., 2018; Lovrich et al., 2004; Wells, 2016). The fact that many SAKs remain untested has resulted in pointed critiques of police investigatory practices in sexual assault cases (Campbell et al., 2019; Campbell &amp;amp; Fehler-Cabral, 2019; Goodman-Williams &amp;amp; Campbell, 2019; Valentine et al., 2019) and has served as a catalyst for mandatory SAK testing policies at both the state and municipal levels over the past decade (Davis et al., 2020).
Prior research has suggested many potential reasons to implement mandatory SAK testing policies. These include: identification of serial rapists, increased reporting of sexual assaults, populating the Combined DNA Index System (CODIS) with offender profiles, and removing bias from the decision-making process for whether to submit a particular SAK (Campbell et al., 2019; Davis et al., 2020; Goodman-Williams &amp;amp; Campbell, 2019; Hendrix et al., 2019; Lovell et al., 2019; Valentine et al., 2019). An additional proposed benefit to mandating SAK testing, which we focus on in this study, is higher rates of arrest for sexual assault (Davis et al., 2020). An increased arrest rate for sexual assault—as a means of holding more offenders accountable and restoring justice to more victims—is a shared goal among police, advocates, researchers, and policymakers. Sexual assault continues to be the most under-reported violent crime in the US (Langton et al., 2012; Lonsway &amp;amp; Archambault, 2012), and criminal justice system attrition among cases that are reported is high (Richards et al., 2019). For example, according to the FBI, in 2018, just 18 percent of rapes reported to law enforcement resulted in an arrest (FBI, 2019), and at least one study suggests that only between 3 and 26 percent of reported sexual assault cases result in a conviction (Lonsway &amp;amp; Archambault, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is a need for scientific evidence in the formulation of crime policy (Gies et al., 2020), surprisingly little attention has been directed at whether mandatory SAK testing policies do in fact increase arrest rates for sexual assault (Hendrix et al., 2019; Strom &amp;amp; Hickman, 2016). If a primary goal of an improved criminal justice response to sexual assault is to provide justice to more victims and hold more offenders accountable, an increase in the sexual assault arrest rate is necessary. Arrests are an important marker of sexual assault investigations (Alderden &amp;amp; Ullman, 2012; Ylang &amp;amp; Holtfreter, 2019) and a required prerequisite to an improved criminal justice response to sexual assault investigations. If mandatory SAK testing policies do not provide a demonstrable improvement in the rate of arrest for sexual assaults, it could result in lost legitimacy for the police, which might in turn decrease victims&#39; propensity to come forward (Murphy &amp;amp; Barkworth, 2014; Sunshine &amp;amp; Tyler, 2003; Tankebe, 2013). Accordingly, research assessing the efficacy of mandatory SAK testing policies is sorely needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current study, we examine the effects of a mandatory SAK testing policy on sexual assault arrests in a large jurisdiction in the western US. We accomplish this by utilizing a novel technique known as Bayesian structural time-series modeling, a type of time-series quasi-experimental method (Brodersen et al., 2015b). Our findings show no effect on the arrest rate for sexual assault and raise significant concerns about the efficacy of mandatory SAK testing policies to increase arrests. Further, they highlight the need to ensure appropriate resources are provided to investigating agencies and crime laboratories when such policies are considered (Wells, 2016), as well as to consider other causes of low sexual assault arrest rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sexual-assault-kits-saks&#34;&gt;Sexual Assault Kits (SAKs)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collection of medical forensic evidence in sexual assault investigations became common practice in the 1980s (Goodman-Williams &amp;amp; Campbell, 2019). It is now routine for law enforcement to encourage sexual assault victims to undergo a forensic interview including a SAK upon reporting an incident. Typically performed by sexual assault nurse examiners (SANEs), SAK examinations include collecting biological evidence, such as semen and saliva, which may be present on victims&#39; bodies post-sexual assault. After collection, SANEs supply the SAK to law enforcement for use in the investigatory process (Valentine et al., 2019). With the availability of the CODIS database, deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) profiles collected during SAK examinations can be compared against DNA profiles of arrestees, convicted offenders, and other SAK evidence and crime scenes from across the United States (Butler, 2005; Jobling &amp;amp; Gill, 2004; Wells et al., 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to identify and evaluate DNA profiles obtained during sexual assault investigations holds significant investigatory power. For example, unknown perpetrators can be identified if their DNA profile is already housed in CODIS. Investigators may also identify serial offenders by linking a specific DNA profile to multiple sexual assault cases and victims (Goodman-Williams &amp;amp; Campbell, 2019; Lovell et al., 2019). The benefits are not just realized in CODIS utilization, however. While a substantial proportion of sexual assault cases hinge on issues of consent, simply being able to confirm that biological evidence collected during a SAK examination belongs to a specific suspect who denies any sexual contact with the victim can be potent evidence of guilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, even with these clear evidentiary benefits, there have been multiple reports over the last decade, from all across the United States, describing how large quantities of SAKs have been left untested in police evidence warehouses (Valentine et al., 2019). For example, in 2002, it was reported that approximately 13,000 SAKs collected in Los Angeles County were never submitted for testing. In 2009, more than 11,000 unsubmitted SAKs were located in a Detroit Police Department evidence warehouse (Hendrix et al., 2019). Similarly, thousands of untested SAKs were found in Cuyahoga County, Ohio (Campbell &amp;amp; Fehler-Cabral, 2019). Of course, the exact number is unknown, as many jurisdictions report being unaware of precisely how many untested SAKs they possess (Keteyian, 2009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the advantages above, why might so many SAKs go untested? Until the recent exposure of large numbers of untested SAKs, the decision to submit SAKs to a crime laboratory for DNA processing was left to individual police investigators&#39; discretion. Paralleling how they pursue investigations for other crimes (Brandl &amp;amp; Frank, 1994; Eck, 1983, 1992; Lum et al., 2018; Scott et al., 2019; Wellford &amp;amp; Cronin, 1999), there are several reasons why investigators might choose not to submit a SAK for testing. First, a non-trivial number of victims do not proceed with investigations once the initial allegation is made (Campbell et al., 2015; Richards et al., 2019; Wells, 2016), thus curtailing the ability to investigate or prosecute the case. Processing SAKs in cases that will not lead to any criminal proceedings/charges is arguably an inefficient use of limited resources (Davis et al., 2020). Second, in most sexual assault cases, the offender is known (Richards et al., 2019), and investigators may conclude that processing SAKs will not yield any probative value to those cases. Third, in some cases, offenders admit to the sexual assault. In cases where a confession is already obtained, the need for DNA evidence may be seen as unnecessary (Davis et al., 2020; Strom &amp;amp; Hickman, 2016). Fourth, investigators become accustomed to factors within cases that determine whether prosecutors will file charges. If the circumstances of a particular case do not meet those standards (i.e., a &amp;lsquo;trial sufficiency&amp;rsquo; standard), investigators may not submit a SAK in order to conserve agency resources. This is referred to as &amp;lsquo;downstream orientation&amp;rsquo; (Alderden &amp;amp; Ullman, 2012; Frohmann, 1991; Pattavina et al., 2016; Spohn &amp;amp; Tellis, 2019; Ylang &amp;amp; Holtfreter, 2019). Finally, investigators may not submit a SAK because they do not think the complainant is credible (Campbell et al., 2015; Davis et al., 2020; Hendrix et al., 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are, however, many theorized advantages to police investigators submitting all SAKs. First, by removing discretion for the submission of SAKs, the presence of extra-legal factors associated with stereotypes about &amp;lsquo;real rape&amp;rsquo; (Estrich, 1987; e.g., victim drug or alcohol use, sex worker status, and antecedent victim &amp;ldquo;risk-taking&amp;rdquo; behavior) that may bias investigators&#39; decision-making are mitigated (Davis et al., 2020). A recent study identified these extra-legal characteristics as the primary influencers of investigator decisions to submit SAKs for testing, which the authors deem &amp;ldquo;justice denied for&amp;hellip;sexual assault victims whose fully collected SAKs were never submitted for analysis&amp;rdquo; (Valentine et al., 2019, p. 3565). Second, any obtained DNA evidence helps corroborate victims&#39; statements, even if the suspect is already known or has confessed (Campbell et al., 2019; Campbell &amp;amp; Fehler-Cabral, 2019). Third, retrieval of DNA profiles from all sexual assault cases will result in the identification and (hopefully) arrest and prosecution of serial offenders (Campbell et al., 2019; Davis et al., 2020; Lovell et al., 2019). Finally, advocates of mandatory SAK testing policies argue arrests, prosecutions, and convictions of sex offenders in general will increase (Davis et al., 2020). This final argument found some empirical support after an additional 600 indictments and 400 convictions were associated with testing SAKs that had previously been backlogged in Cuyahoga County, Ohio (Lovell et al., 2018). What remains unclear is whether these same expectations hold for mandatory testing of new SAKs, a discussion we return to later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are convincing normative arguments for the viewpoints described above. However, the past decade has seen those advocating for mandatory testing policies gaining ground in the policy sphere. According to &lt;a href=&#34;endthebacklog.org&#34;&gt;endthebacklog.org&lt;/a&gt; (2020), a program of the national nonprofit organization Joyful Heart Foundation, in 2019 alone, 103 bills were introduced in 35 states and Washington DC explicitly addressing concerns about the handling of SAKs. Further, 12 states have passed comprehensive SAK reform, including (1) inventorying and testing of all untested SAKs, and (2) timely testing of newly obtained SAKs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;outcome-evidence-from-texas&#34;&gt;Outcome Evidence from Texas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the evidence above, the question remains: do prospective mandatory testing policies achieve the desired outcomes? With the exception of identifying serial offenders (Campbell et al., 2019; Lovell et al., 2019), little work has been conducted to test these policies&#39; outcomes. To our knowledge, only one other empirical test of prospective mandatory SAK testing policies has been undertaken. Davis et al. (2020) examined the policy outcomes of a compulsory statewide SAK testing law in Texas, otherwise known as Senate Bill 1636 (SB 1636). Texas was one of the first states to enact state legislation requiring the testing of all SAKs. In 2011, SB 1636 was passed, mandating that law enforcement agencies submit SAKs to a crime laboratory within 30 days of receipt. Advocates for the bill anticipated that it would lead to an increase in sexual assault reporting, as well as an increase in sexual assault arrests, prosecutions, and convictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to their hypotheses, Davis et al. (2020) did not find support for increased sexual assault reporting, sexual assault arrests, or sexual assault court filings and convictions across a 4-year pre- and post-policy implementation period. Davis et al. report that &amp;ldquo;[u]niversal testing of DNA in sexual assault cases, by itself, may be insufficient to promote meaningful changes in reporting and criminal justice system indicators that some may have expected&amp;rdquo; (p. 433). They identify inadequate crime laboratory funding as one primary possible reason for their null findings, as the crime laboratory was overwhelmed with the substantial increase in SAK submissions, resulting in lengthy turnaround times for analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another possible reason for Davis et al.&amp;rsquo;s (2020) null findings is that their study tests the effects of SB 1636 on the crimes of &amp;ldquo;sexual assault&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;aggravated sexual assault.&amp;rdquo; It is unclear from their study which specific crimes these terms encompass. Clear operationalization is vital when assessing the possible effects of mandatory testing policies because the term sexual assault can be ambiguous. That is, sexual assault encompasses not only rape but also other illegal behaviors, such as unwanted touching or sexual harassment in the workplace. When examining the effect of a mandatory SAK testing policy, specificity is critical. In the interest of greater specificity, we closely examine the effects of a mandatory testing policy on arrests for rape. Throughout this manuscript, we may reference &amp;ldquo;sexual assault&amp;rdquo; when discussing sexual violence in general, but when discussing the mandatory testing policy&amp;rsquo;s effects, we are explicitly referring to rape. Finally, Davis et al.&amp;rsquo;s (2020) study examined the effect of a mandatory SAK testing policy across an entire state, which may have masked important variation across jurisdictions therein. Our research examines one jurisdiction&amp;rsquo;s experience with mandatory SAK testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-current-study&#34;&gt;The Current Study&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current study, we focus on arrests for rape. While there are conflicting findings in the limited research literature examining whether analysis of previously untested SAKs leads to an increase in positive case outcomes (Campbell &amp;amp; Fehler-Cabral, 2019; Peterson et al., 2012), we examine the effects of requiring testing of all SAKs at the time they enter the criminal justice system. The only study that we are aware of that tested whether prospective mandatory SAK submission policies increase sexual assault arrests found that they do not (Davis et al., 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some indication that SAK testing by crime laboratories enhances criminal justice processing of sexual assault cases (Valentine et al., 2019). However, it is unclear if improved case outcomes are because of the tested SAK itself, or if cases with tested SAKs are already more likely than other cases to result in positive case outcomes due to legal or extra-legal factors. Further, Davis et al. (2020) found a non-significant decreasing trend in sexual assault arrest rates in their study following implementation of a mandatory testing policy. Davis and colleagues indicated that this was possibly due to a failure to provide adequate resources for the entire investigatory system following the mandatory SAK testing policy (specifically crime laboratory resources). The jurisdiction we studied experienced a similar inadequacy of secondary resourcing upon policy implementation. With this in mind, we developed the following research hypothesis regarding the policy effect on the arrest rate for rape:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hypothesis: Mandatory testing of SAKs will not lead to an increase in the proportion of rape reports that result in an arrest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-and-method&#34;&gt;Data and Method&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data&#34;&gt;Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We utilize reported crime and arrest data from an anonymous municipal police department that serves a capital city in the western United States (hereafter referred to as &amp;ldquo;Westland&amp;rdquo;). The Westland Police Department (WPD) provides full-spectrum policing services to a mixed urban core and suburban service area with an estimated nighttime population of 200,000 residents and a metropolitan population of over one million. The department employs approximately 600 sworn officers and has a specified unit within its investigation division responsible for investigating all sexual assault allegations (a special victims unit).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, WPD came under public criticism regarding past non-testing of SAKs for sexual assault investigations. From 2004 through 2013, approximately 77% of all SAKs received by WPD were never submitted to a crime laboratory for processing. As a result, and despite agency leadership arguing for a more limited policy, a city ordinance was passed, requiring all SAKs received by WPD be submitted to a crime laboratory for analysis within 30 days of receipt. The policy was implemented on November 1, 2014, and was effective immediately. This sharp implementation is a critical aspect of our research design, as it allows us to leverage the power of a natural experiment to analyze trends during the pre- and post-implementation periods. With immediate effect, every SAK that came into WPD&amp;rsquo;s special victims unit on or after November 1, 2014, was submitted to the state crime laboratory for testing. When a series of measures is broken up by the introduction of an intervention that occurs at a specific point in time, time-series analysis is appropriate (Davis et al., 2020; Shadish et al., 2002). The enactment of the mandatory SAK testing policy in Westland provides an opportunity for a time-series quasi-experiment to ascertain the impact (if any) of the policy on arrest rates for rape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;measures&#34;&gt;Measures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rape arrest rates&lt;/strong&gt;. Our measure of rape arrest rates is constructed from agency-level data. By policy, at WPD a SAK is obtained whenever possible in all reported incidents of rape. This policy is because, unlike some forms of sexual assault, there is a high likelihood of obtaining biological evidence containing DNA after a rape is committed. When taking a sexual assault complaint, officers in Westland have to designate the type of crime being reported in the agency&amp;rsquo;s report writing system using a National Crime Information Center (NCIC) code. There are many designated codes related to crimes of sexual assault. For example, there are several sexual assault codes for child molestation, sexual assaults not involving penetration, rape, and more. By creating our measure with these codes at the agency level, we restrict our study to the crime of rape, as defined in the studied jurisdiction. The state in which Westland is located defines rape as &amp;ldquo;sexual intercourse with another person without the victim&amp;rsquo;s consent.&amp;rdquo; We documented the total number of rapes reported to WPD, along with the total number of arrests for rape, from 2010 through 2019, providing 120 monthly time-series measures. We defined an arrest as any instance in which a person was arrested, summoned to court, or had a warrant issued for their arrest. The arrest rate was calculated by dividing the number of arrests for rape in each month by the total number of rapes reported each month. &lt;strong&gt;Figure 1&lt;/strong&gt; displays the time-series data for rape arrests and reports in Westland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/figure1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Arrest and Report Data for Westland PD, 2010&amp;ndash;2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;model-description&#34;&gt;Model Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Bayesian structural time-series model (BSTS) is a state-space time-series model that includes one component of state as a linear regression on the predictors. While we summarize the method below, a much more technical explanation of BSTS modeling is provided by Brodersen et al. (2015b), the developers of the method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concisely, BSTS is best described as an observation equation, which links the observed data with an observed latent state and transition equation. The transition equation describes the development of the latent state over time. The observation equation is defined as $$y_t = Z_t^T α_t + ε_t$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where $y_t$ is a scalar observation (i.e., arrest rate), $Z_t$ is an output vector, and $α_t$ is the unobserved latent state; $ε_t ~ N(0, σ_t^2)$ is independent of all other unknowns and is a scalar observation error with variance $σ_t$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition equation is defined as $$α_(t+1)  = T_t α_t+ R_t η_t$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where $α_t$ is the unobserved latent state, $T_t$ is the transition matrix, and $R_t$ is the control matrix; $η_t \sim N(0, Q_t)$ is independent of all other unknowns and describes the system error with a state-diffusion matrix $Q_t$. $R_t η_t$ allows the inclusion of seasonality in the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BSTS models infer causal impact by predicting the counterfactual treatment response in a synthetic control that would have occurred if no intervention had taken place. That is, rather than comparing the experimental group to a nonequivalent control group, BSTS models use a synthetic control to construct the counterfactual to estimate the treatment effect. This synthetic control is constructed by using the time-series behavior of the experimental group prior to and after the intervention, as well as combining control variables that are predictive of the target series prior to the intervention. As long as the control variables did not receive the intervention, it is reasonable to assume the relationship between the treatment and the control variables that existed prior to the intervention would continue if the treatment had no effect. As such, a plausible estimate of the counterfactual time-series can be estimated up to the point where the relationship between treatment and controls are no longer stationary because of the treatment (Brodersen et al., 2015c; de Vocht et al., 2017; Liu &amp;amp; Fabbri, 2016; Ratcliffe et al., 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use of BSTS models are ideal for social science (Brodersen et al., 2015b), and have been used successfully in other criminological studies to estimate violence reduction as a result of gang arrests (Ratcliffe et al., 2017); the deterrence effect of unarmed private patrols (Liu &amp;amp; Fabbri, 2016); and the effect alcohol licensing policies have on crime (de Vocht et al., 2017). Further, BSTS models are preferred to Auto Regressive Integrated Moving Average (ARIMA) models when examining crime data because crime data is low-volume count data, which may be inappropriate for ARIMA modeling (Ratcliffe et al., 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Counterfactual predictor.&lt;/strong&gt; A key component of utilizing BSTS modeling is the identification of appropriate predictors. Predictors are linearly regressed onto the observed values, creating the composite synthetic control series (Brodersen et al., 2015b; Ratcliffe et al., 2017). To build the synthetic control for the time-series, we turn to other violent crimes. It is well established that violent crimes tend to track with each other across time (Latzer, 2016; Lonsway &amp;amp; Archambault, 2012; Yung, 2013). To ascertain whether arrest rates for rape are associated with arrest rates for other violent crimes in Westland, we examined the arrest rates for aggravated assault, domestic violence aggravated assault, simple assault, robbery, and homicide. We found that the arrest rates for aggravated assault and domestic violence aggravated assault most closely mirrored the arrest rate for rape from January 2010 through October 2014 (the pre-intervention time-period). We plot the arrest rate for rape with the arrest rates for aggravated assault and domestic violence aggravated assault in Westland in &lt;strong&gt;Figure 2&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/figure2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Arrest Rates for Rape and Other Violent Crimes in Westland, Jan 2010 through Oct 2014&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the above analysis, the arrest rates for aggravated assault and domestic violence aggravated assault in Westland are utilized to construct the synthetic control. Importantly, the arrest rate for aggravated assault and domestic violence aggravated assault would not plausibly be affected by the mandatory SAK testing policy. Moreover, as mentioned previously, WPD employs a specialized detective unit to investigate all sexual assaults. As such, detectives investigating aggravated assaults (investigated by a violent crimes unit at WPD) and domestic violence aggravated assault (investigated by a domestic violence unit at WPD) would not be affected by this policy. Thus, any change in the rate of arrests for rape that is not also observed in the rate of arrests for either of the aggravated assault categories may reasonably be attributed to the mandatory submission policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;analysis-and-results&#34;&gt;Analysis and Results&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used the R package &lt;code&gt;CausalImpact&lt;/code&gt; (Brodersen et al., 2015a) to conduct the analysis. The model uses a response variable comprised of the monthly arrest rate for rape, and the predictor variables: the arrest rates for aggravated assault and domestic violence aggravated assault. The BSTS model was structured to allow for a seasonal parameter to reflect any yearly cyclical behavior on the arrest rate for rape (Mcdowall et al., 2012; Mcdowall &amp;amp; Curtis, 2015).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pre-intervention time series began in January 2010 and ended in October 2014, as the mandatory SAK testing policy was enacted on November 1, 2014. The post-intervention time-series began in November 2014 and continued through December of 2019. Accordingly, the pre-intervention series is 58 data points in length, with a post-intervention length of 62 months. Ten thousand Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) samples were drawn for the analysis in each model. Ninety-five percent Bayesian posterior distribution credible intervals were generated. Results for the model assessing change in the arrest rate for rape are presented in &lt;strong&gt;Figure 3&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frequentist analog to a credible interval is a confidence interval, yet the two concepts are statistically different. In a frequentist paradigm, confidence intervals are based on repeated sampling theory. A 95% confidence interval indicates that 95 out of 100 replications of exactly the same experiment will capture the fixed, but unknown, regression coefficient. A credible interval can be interpreted as the probability that the population parameter is between the upper and lower bounds of the credible interval, based on the available information (Van de Schoot &amp;amp; Depaoli, 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/figure3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Effect of Mandatory SAK Submission Policy on Rape Arrest Rate, Monthly Data 2010 through 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3&lt;/strong&gt; contains three panels. The panel labeled &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; shows the data and a counterfactual prediction for the post-treatment period. The counterfactual prediction is the horizontal dashed line, with a corresponding 95% credible interval surrounding it. The solid line represents the observed data. The panel labeled &amp;ldquo;pointwise&amp;rdquo; represents the pointwise causal effect, as estimated by the model. That is, it shows the difference between observed data and counterfactual predictions. The panel labeled &amp;ldquo;cumulative&amp;rdquo; visualizes the cumulative effect of the intervention post-treatment by summing the pointwise contributions from the second panel. The dashed vertical line represents the intervention date (i.e., November 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 1: Causal Impact Posterior Inference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Average&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;SD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;95% CI&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actual Arrest Rate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.097&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Predicted Arrest Rate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.045&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[0.029, 0.200]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Absolute Effect&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.045&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[-0.110, 0.069]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Relative Effect&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-16%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;39%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[-92%, 59%]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As indicated in &lt;strong&gt;Table 1&lt;/strong&gt;, the enactment of the mandatory SAK submission policy at WPD was associated with a decrease in the arrest rate for rape. During the post-intervention period, the arrest rate for rape had an average value of .097. By contrast, in the absence of an intervention, we would have expected a counterfactual average of .120. The 95% credible interval of the counterfactual prediction is [0.029, 0.200]. Subtracting this prediction from the observed response yields an estimate of the absolute causal effect the intervention had on the arrest rate for rape (-.018), resulting in a 16% relative decrease. The posterior probability of the observed negative effect is .66. In other words, although it appears the intervention may have exerted a negative effect on the arrest rate for rape, the effect is not statistically significant by conventional standards (i.e., the probability of obtaining this effect by chance is .34). In sum, we observed a downward trend that departs from the counterfactual we estimated. However, we cannot say with a considerable probability that the observed negative trend was a result of the policy implementation. The most conservative interpretation is that, consistent with our hypothesis, the policy implementation did not have an effect on rape arrest rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;discussion&#34;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been calls within academic, advocacy, and policy circles over the past several years to increase accountability for those who commit sexual violence (Sacco &amp;amp; James, 2015; Valentine et al., 2019; Watkins, 2019). One proposed policy intervention to meet these appeals is that of mandatory SAK testing policies. It has been theorized that requiring all SAKs to be submitted to crime labs for DNA analysis will increase the ability to identify and hold offenders accountable (Campbell et al., 2019; Campbell &amp;amp; Fehler-Cabral, 2019; Davis et al., 2020; Lovell et al., 2019; Valentine et al., 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In search of these desirable outcomes, as of 2019, 12 states have passed comprehensive SAK reform, which includes mandatory testing of newly obtained SAKs (Endthebacklog.org, 2020). Methodologically rigorous evaluations of these policies are scant (Hendrix et al., 2019; Strom &amp;amp; Hickman, 2016), but absolutely critical. If mandatory testing policies are not producing the desired results, further investigation is necessary to understand if and how policies could be amended or supplemented to better achieve the desired results. That is, if arrest rates for sexual assault are not increasing, there must be other determinative factors at play that should be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we examined the above question. We tested the effect of a mandatory SAK testing policy on the arrest rate for rapes in one jurisdiction after a mandatory SAK testing policy was implemented. We accomplished this by using a Bayesian structural time-series model with 120 longitudinal data points. As hypothesized, our model found that the mandatory SAK testing policy did not lead to an increase in the arrest rate for rape, but instead had a null, or possibly a negative, effect (probability = .66).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears then, at least in Westland, a mandatory SAK testing policy did not have the effect of increasing the arrest rate for rapes&amp;mdash;an often-stated goal of those who advocate for such policies (Davis et al., 2020). The implementation of mandatory testing policies &amp;ldquo;is not merely to test rape kits, but to investigate and prosecute the reported sexual assaults associated with these kits&amp;rdquo; (Campbell &amp;amp; Fehler-Cabral, 2019, p. 2). We agree. We call attention to several other studies, as well as anecdotal evidence obtained from conversations with the investigators at WPD, to help explain these findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only other similar study we are aware of examines the effect of a statewide mandatory submission policy in Texas. Davis et al. (2020) found that implementing a statewide mandatory SAK submission policy did not increase sexual assault arrests or convictions, but did increase the workload for investigators and crime laboratories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While not statistically significant, much like our analysis Davis et al. (2020) finds a general decrease in the sexual assault arrest rate after the mandatory testing policy implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The large influx of SAKs for testing created a backlog for incoming cases (not to be confused with previously untested kits). Through interviews with sexual assault investigators and crime lab personnel, Davis and colleagues found that after implementation of the mandatory testing policy, completion of analysis for newly incoming SAKs was taking 10-11 months. Investigators stated that having to wait up to a year for SAK analysis results commonly prompted victims to drop out of the criminal justice process. Davis et al. warn that mandated testing may be insufficient to promote meaningful changes without sufficient additional funding directed to the affected agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davis et al.&amp;rsquo;s (2020) description of underfunded crime laboratory resources following a mandatory SAK testing policy is mirrored in the state where Westland is located. In 2017, the state legislature passed a new state law, mandating submission of all SAKs throughout the state, effective immediately (much like the municipal SAK policy implemented solely in Westland in 2014). During the 2018 legislative session, news stories reported that the state crime laboratory could not keep up with testing demand. In response, the state legislature gave law enforcement agencies slightly expanded time frames to come into compliance. In 2020, the state crime laboratory requested millions in additional funding due to a 535% increase in SAK submissions between 2012 and 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hendrix et al. (2019) also call attention to a lack of resources for SAK testing. While they did not test the implementation of a mandatory testing policy specifically, their findings are instructive. Hendrix et al. found that a lack of resources primarily drives non-submission of SAKs by agencies without mandatory testing policies. The researchers found that the most important resource input, when attempting to increase the use of SAKs, is increasing the number of detectives assigned to investigating sexual assault cases. In their study, SAK submission increased 24% for every 100% increase in detectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, a common explanation for not submitting a SAK was the inability of crime labs to produce timely results. This limitation is relevant to our findings for the following reasons. Based on Hendrix et al.&amp;rsquo;s findings, voluntary investigative submission of SAKs rises with increased investigatory resources. However, a continuing reason to not submit SAKs is the inability of crime laboratories to provide timely turnaround on analyses, a concern echoed elsewhere (e.g., Strom &amp;amp; Hickman, 2016). Policies may be implemented that require all SAKs to be submitted, but without an adequate increase in resources for investigators and the crime laboratories responsible for analyzing the submitted SAKs, mandatory policies may harm victims in the sense that both investigating agencies and crime labs are logistically overwhelmed. This logjam may increase turnaround time on SAK analyses, and thus increase turnaround time on the entire investigation. The lengthy timeline between victim reporting and law enforcement action may lead to frustration from victims, and ultimately their withdrawal from the justice process (Kääriäinen &amp;amp; Sirén, 2011; Tarling &amp;amp; Morris, 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anecdotal evidence from interviews with investigators at WPD lends credence to this possibility. Before mandatory SAK submission policy implementation, investigators were already waiting extended periods for SAK DNA analysis results, ranging from six months to one year. Following the policy implementation, the average turnaround time for SAK DNA analyses increased to between eighteen months to two years. Investigators reported victim withdrawal due to these ever-growing wait times for SAK testing. The increased delay overlapped with a substantial increase in investigatory resources. From the policy implementation to 2018, the detective unit responsible for investigating sexual assaults increased by a third&amp;mdash;from six detectives to eight detectives. Three additional detectives have been added since 2018, indicating WPD is still attempting to balance its investigative resources. At the least, the nearly doubling of detectives in the special victims unit since policy implementation suggests that whatever mechanism drives the stagnant (or decreasing) arrest rate is not related to a decrease in the number of investigators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It must be considered that perhaps submission of all SAKs simply does not provide the additional evidence needed to increase accountability for sexual assault offenders. While several studies indicate that testing SAKs is associated with positive case outcomes (Valentine et al., 2019), it must be remembered that the vast majority of sexual assault cases involve known perpetrators (Richards et al., 2019). If the hope is that DNA analysis from SAKs will increase arrest and prosecution for sexual assaults, expectations may need to be tempered. That is, DNA evidence is not especially helpful when prosecutors are trying to prove a lack of consent (Spohn &amp;amp; Tellis, 2014). While an increase in DNA profiles in CODIS will likely assist in identifying serial rapists, DNA evidence from non-serial sexual assaults where the suspect is known and claims consent may not provide the benefit desired by proponents of mandatory SAK submission policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it should also be considered that investigator discretion was interpreting the &amp;lsquo;downstream orientation&amp;rsquo; of prosecuting entities correctly in the majority of sexual assault cases (Alderden &amp;amp; Ullman, 2012; Frohmann, 1991; Richards et al., 2019; Spohn &amp;amp; Tellis, 2014, 2019). Prosecutorial discretion is a major source of influence in the handling of criminal cases (Mourtgos &amp;amp; Adams, 2019; Pfaff, 2017). While calls for improved sexual assault investigatory practices (Campbell et al., 2019; Campbell &amp;amp; Fehler-Cabral, 2019; Goodman-Williams &amp;amp; Campbell, 2019; Valentine et al., 2019) are warranted, perhaps additional attention should be paid to prosecutorial handling of sexual assault cases. So, while SAK testing may be mandated, and investigatory resources may be expanded and improved, increased accountability for sexual assault perpetrators remains dampened if sexual assault cases are not charged and prosecuted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policymakers, victims, and the public should continue to demand that sexual assault investigations receive full and proper treatment. SAK testing policies are a necessary component, but as our results show, mandating SAK testing is not sufficient on its own. We join Davis et al. (2020) in their emphasis on recommending elevated funding of the system around sexual assault investigations. If adequate funding and resources are not provided to the investigating agencies and crime laboratories concurrently with these policies, increased offender accountability is unlikely to occur, as outlined in our study, as well as other empirical research (Davis et al., 2020). Also, resources must be invested in other &amp;lsquo;victim-facing&amp;rsquo; services, particularly victim advocates who serve as liaisons between victims and the criminal justice system (Rich &amp;amp; Seffrin, 2013). Research demonstrates that victim advocates are associated with positive victim outcomes, including victim engagement with law enforcement and prosecutors (Patterson &amp;amp; Campbell, 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that mandatory SAK testing is likely associated with increased wait times, victim advocates may be critical to keeping victims informed, and thus engaged in the process. Other potential components of a holistic approach to SAKs include online tracking systems that allow victims to follow the progress of their SAK in real-time without having to work through law enforcement officers or victim services (Carlisle, 2019). Again, given the historical undertesting of SAKs, increased criminal justice system transparency is likely critical to building and sustaining trust from victims of sexual assault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations-and-future-research&#34;&gt;Limitations and Future Research&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We contribute important findings to this nascent body of knowledge, but this research is not without limitations. First, this study looks at a single jurisdiction. WPD is a large agency with approximately 600 sworn officers, with jurisdiction of a major metropolitan capital city in the Western US, and with a dedicated special victims unit. Though our results build on similar findings (Davis et al., 2020), that study also took place in a Western US state. To the degree that there may be regional differences, it is not clear how our findings will generalize to other parts of the US, or to smaller, exurban, suburban, and rural communities. We suspect that given the more considerable resources available to large metropolitan police forces, and the greater specialization of investigators found there, non-metropolitan jurisdictions may see negative effects of even greater magnitude and certainty than found in our study. However, that question must be answered in future research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second limitation is related to the scope of our research. We do not propose or pursue a full accounting of the costs, benefits, outputs, and outcomes of the mandatory SAK testing policy, but restrict our analysis to the primary indicator of clearance by arrest of rape cases. There are likely other benefits and costs incurred by the policy, and we encourage a fuller accounting in future work. Related to both generalizability and scope concerns, our single jurisdiction is located in a state that only recently passed a law mandating SAK testing across the state. While we are not able to analyze the results of that statewide law, we encourage other researchers to pursue similar research and build the empirical foundation for understanding the effect of mandatory SAK testing policies and laws. For a host of ethical and logistical reasons, it is not likely that a true randomized control trial will be available. As demonstrated here, Bayesian structural time-series provides an accessible and relatively easy method to leverage the implementation of those policies with natural experimental designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mandatory testing of SAKs has been rapidly adopted in criminal justice investigations, but to date, the empirical record for understanding the effects of those policies has been extremely limited. Our findings suggest that following implementation of such a policy, the arrest rate in cases most likely to result in a SAK being performed showed, at best, no change, and a substantial probability of a decrease. These outcomes should give policy makers and police administrators pause. They suggest that going forward, a substantial increase in resources is necessary across the investigative and victim service systems before the desired change in criminal justice system outcomes are realized. Further, reforms and policy changes other than mandatory SAK testing policies are likely required to increase accountability for sexual assault offenders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\newpage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alderden, M. A., &amp;amp; Ullman, S. E. (2012). Creating a more complete and current picture: Examining police and prosecutor decision-making when processing sexual assault cases. &lt;em&gt;Violence Against Women&lt;/em&gt;, 18(5), 525&amp;ndash;551. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1077801212453867&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1077801212453867&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brandl, S. G., &amp;amp; Frank, J. (1994). The relationship between evidence, detective effort, and the disposition of burglary and robbery investigations. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Police&lt;/em&gt;, 13(3), 149&amp;ndash;168.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brodersen, K. H., Gallusser, F., Koehler, J., Remy, N., &amp;amp; Scott, S. L. (2015a). &lt;code&gt;CausalImpact&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://google.github.io/CausalImpact/&#34;&gt;http://google.github.io/CausalImpact/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brodersen, K. H., Gallusser, F., Koehler, J., Remy, N., &amp;amp; Scott, S. L. (2015b). Inferring causal impact using bayesian structural time-series models. &lt;em&gt;Annals of Applied Statistics&lt;/em&gt;, 9(1), 247&amp;ndash;274. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1214/14-AOAS788&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1214/14-AOAS788&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brodersen, K. H., Gallusser, F., Koehler, J., Remy, N., &amp;amp; Scott, S. L. (2015c). Inferring causal impact using bayesian structural time-series models. &lt;em&gt;Annals of Applied Statistics&lt;/em&gt;, 9(1), 247&amp;ndash;274. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1214/14-AOAS788&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1214/14-AOAS788&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butler, J. M. (2005). &lt;em&gt;Forensic DNA typing: Biology, technology, and genetics of STR markers&lt;/em&gt; (2nd ed.). Elsevier Academic Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campbell, R., Feeney, H., Goodman-Williams, R., Sharma, D. B., &amp;amp; Pierce, S. J. (2019). Connecting the dots: Identifying suspected serial sexual offenders through forensic DNA evidence. &lt;em&gt;Psychology of Violence&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/vio0000243&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/vio0000243&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campbell, R., &amp;amp; Fehler-Cabral, G. (2019). The best way out is always through: Addressing the problem of untested sexual assault kits (SAKs) through multidisciplinary collaboration. &lt;em&gt;Victims &amp;amp; Offenders&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/15564886.2019.1679309&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/15564886.2019.1679309&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campbell, R., Fehler-Cabral, G., Pierce, S. J., Sharma, D. B., Bybee, D., Shaw, J., Horsford, S., &amp;amp; Feeney, H. (2015). The Detroit sexual assault kit (SAK) action research project (ARP), final report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlisle, M. (2019). A new system to ensure that sexual assault cases aren&amp;rsquo;t forgotten. &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davis, R. C., Auchter, B., Wells, W., Camp, T., &amp;amp; Howley, S. (2020). The effects of legislation mandating DNA testing in sexual assault cases: Results in Texas. &lt;em&gt;Violence Against Women&lt;/em&gt;, 26(5), 417&amp;ndash;437. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1077801219838330&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1077801219838330&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;de Vocht, F., Tilling, K., Pliakas, T., Angus, C., Egan, M., Brennan, A., Campbell, R., &amp;amp; Hickman, M. (2017). The intervention effect of local alcohol licensing policies on hospital admission and crime: A natural experiment using a novel Bayesian synthetic time-series method. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Epidemiology &amp;amp; Community Health&lt;/em&gt;, 71(9), 912&amp;ndash;918. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1136/jech-2017-208931&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1136/jech-2017-208931&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eck, J. E. (1983). &lt;em&gt;Solving crimes: The investigation of burglary and robbery&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eck, J. E. (1992). &lt;em&gt;Solving crimes: The investigation of burglary and robbery&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endthebacklog.org. (2020). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.endthebacklog.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.endthebacklog.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estrich, S. (1987). &lt;em&gt;Real rape&lt;/em&gt;. Harvard University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FBI. (2019). Crime in the U.S. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ucr.fbi.gov/crime-in-the-u.s&#34;&gt;https://ucr.fbi.gov/crime-in-the-u.s&lt;/a&gt; Frohmann, L. (1991). Discrediting victims&#39; allegations of sexual assault: Prosecutorial accounts of case rejections. &lt;em&gt;Social Problems&lt;/em&gt;, 38(2), 213&amp;ndash;226.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gies, S. V., Healy, E., &amp;amp; Stephenson, R. (2020). The evidence of effectiveness: Beyond the methodological standards. &lt;em&gt;Justice Evaluation Journal&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/24751979.2020.1727296&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/24751979.2020.1727296&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodman-Williams, R., &amp;amp; Campbell, R. (2019). How to right a wrong: Empirically evaluating whether victim, offender, and assault characteristics can inform rape kit testing policies. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Trauma &amp;amp; Dissociation&lt;/em&gt;, 20(3), 388&amp;ndash;303. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/15299732.2019.1592645&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/15299732.2019.1592645&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hendrix, J. A., Strom, K. J., Parish, W. J., Melton, P. A., &amp;amp; Young, A. R. (2019). An examination of sexual assault kit submission efficiencies among a nationally representative sample of law enforcement agencies. &lt;em&gt;Criminal Justice Policy Review&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0887403419884730&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0887403419884730&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jobling, M. A., &amp;amp; Gill, P. (2004). Encoded evidence: DNA in forensic analysis. &lt;em&gt;Nature Reviews Genetics&lt;/em&gt;, 5(10), 739&amp;ndash;751. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/nrg1455&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/nrg1455&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kääriäinen, J., &amp;amp; Sirén, R. (2011). Trust in the police, generalized trust and reporting crime. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Criminology&lt;/em&gt;, 8(1), 65&amp;ndash;81. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1477370810376562&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1477370810376562&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keteyian, A. (2009). Exclusive: Rape in America: Justice denied. In CBS News. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/exclusive-rape-in-america-justice-denied/&#34;&gt;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/exclusive-rape-in-america-justice-denied/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langton, L., Berzofsky, M., Krebs, C., &amp;amp; Smiley-McDonald, H. (2012). BJS Special Report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latzer, B. (2016). &lt;em&gt;The rise and fall of violent crime in America&lt;/em&gt;. Encounter Books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu, P., &amp;amp; Fabbri, M. (2016). More eyes, (no guns,) less crime: Estimating the effects of unarmed private patrols on crime using a Bayesian structural time-series model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lonsway, K. A., &amp;amp; Archambault, J. (2012). The &amp;ldquo;justicegGap&amp;rdquo; for sexual assault cases: Future directions for research and reform. &lt;em&gt;Violence Against Women&lt;/em&gt;, 18(2), 145&amp;ndash;168. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1077801212440017&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1077801212440017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lovell, R., Huang, W., Overman, L., Flannery, D., &amp;amp; Klingenstein, J. (2019). Offending histories and typologies of suspected sexual offenders identified via untested sexual assault kits. &lt;em&gt;Criminal Justice and Behavior&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0093854819896385&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0093854819896385&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lovell, R., Luminais, M., Flannery, D. J., Bell, R., &amp;amp; Kyker, B. (2018). Describing the process and quantifying the outcomes of the Cuyahoga County sexual assault kit initiative. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Criminal Justice&lt;/em&gt;, 57, 106&amp;ndash;115. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcrimjus.2018.05.012&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcrimjus.2018.05.012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lovrich, N. P., Pratt, T. C., Gaffney, M., Johnson, C., Asplen, C., Hurst, L., &amp;amp; Schellberg, T. (2004). National forensic DNA study report, final report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lum, C., Wellford, C. F., Scott, T., Vovak, H., &amp;amp; Scherer, J. A. (2018). Identifying effective investigative practices: A national study using trajectory analysis, case studies, and investigative data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mcdowall, D., &amp;amp; Curtis, K. M. (2015). Seasonal variation in homicide and assault across large U.S. cities. &lt;em&gt;Homicide Studies&lt;/em&gt;, 19(4), 303&amp;ndash;325. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1088767914536985&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1088767914536985&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mcdowall, D., Loftin, C., &amp;amp; Pate, M. (2012). Seasonal cycles in crime. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Quantitative Criminology&lt;/em&gt;, 28(3), 389&amp;ndash;410. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mourtgos, S. M., &amp;amp; Adams, I. T. (2019). The effect of prosecutorial actions on deterrence: A county-level analysis. &lt;em&gt;Criminal Justice Policy Review&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0887403419829201&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0887403419829201&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murphy, K., &amp;amp; Barkworth, J. (2014). Victim willingness to report crime to police: Does procedural justice or outcome matter most? &lt;em&gt;Victims &amp;amp; Offenders&lt;/em&gt;, 9(2), 178&amp;ndash;204. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/15564886.2013.872744&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/15564886.2013.872744&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office of the Press Secretary. (2015). Fact sheet: Investments to reduce the national rape kit backlog and combat violence against women. &lt;a href=&#34;https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/the-press-office/2015/03/16/fact-sheet-investments-reduce-national-rape-kit-backlog-and-combat-viole&#34;&gt;https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/the-press-office/2015/03/16/fact-sheet-investments-reduce-national-rape-kit-backlog-and-combat-viole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pattavina, A., Morabito, M., &amp;amp; Williams, L. M. (2016). Examining connections between the police and prosecution in sexual assault case processing: Does the use of exceptional clearance facilitate a downstream orientation? &lt;em&gt;Victims &amp;amp; Offenders&lt;/em&gt;, 11(2), 315&amp;ndash;334. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/15564886.2015.1046622&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/15564886.2015.1046622&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patterson, D., &amp;amp; Campbell, R. (2010). Why rape survivors participate in the criminal justice system. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Community Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, 38(2), 191&amp;ndash;205. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/jcop.20359&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/jcop.20359&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peterson, J., Johnson, D., Herz, D., Graziano, L., &amp;amp; Oehler, T. (2012). Sexual assault kit backlog study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfaff, J. F. (2017). &lt;em&gt;Locked in: The true causes of mass incarceration and how to achieve real reform&lt;/em&gt;. Basic Books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ratcliffe, J. H., Perenzin, A., &amp;amp; Sorg, E. T. (2017). Operation Thumbs Down A quasi-experimental evaluation of an FBI gang takedown in South Central Los Angeles. &lt;em&gt;Policing: An International Journal of Police Stategies &amp;amp; Management&lt;/em&gt;, 40(2), 442&amp;ndash;458. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1108/PIJPSM-01-2016-0004&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1108/PIJPSM-01-2016-0004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rich, K., &amp;amp; Seffrin, P. (2013). Police officers&#39; collaboration with rape victim advocates: Barriers and facilitators. &lt;em&gt;Violence and Victims&lt;/em&gt;, 28(4), 687&amp;ndash;696.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richards, T. N., Skubak, M. S., &amp;amp; Wright, E. M. (2019). When victims refuse and prosecutors decline: Examining exceptional clearance in sexual assault cases. &lt;em&gt;Crime &amp;amp; Delinquency&lt;/em&gt;, 65(4), 474&amp;ndash;498. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0011128719828351&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0011128719828351&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sacco, L. N., &amp;amp; James, N. (2015). Backlog of sexual assault evidence: In brief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott, T. L., Wellford, C., Lum, C., &amp;amp; Vovak, H. (2019). Variability of crime clearance among police agencies. &lt;em&gt;Police Quarterly&lt;/em&gt;, 22(1), 82&amp;ndash;111. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1098611118796597&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1098611118796597&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shadish, W. R., Cook, T. D., &amp;amp; Campbell, D. T. (2002). Quasi-experiments: Interrupted time-series designs. Experimental and quasi-experimental designs for generalized causal inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spohn, C., &amp;amp; Tellis, K. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Policing and prosecuting sexual assault: Inside the criminal justice system&lt;/em&gt;. Lynne Reinner Publishers, Inc. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1145/1242421.1242427&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1145/1242421.1242427&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spohn, C., &amp;amp; Tellis, K. (2019). Sexual assault case outcomes: Disentangling the overlapping decisions of police and prosecutors. &lt;em&gt;Justice Quarterly&lt;/em&gt;, 36(3), 383&amp;ndash;411. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/07418825.2018.1429645&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/07418825.2018.1429645&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strom, K. J., &amp;amp; Hickman, M. J. (2016). Untested sexual assault kits: Searching for an empirical foundation to guide forensic case processing decisions. &lt;em&gt;Criminology &amp;amp; Public Policy&lt;/em&gt;, 15(2), 593&amp;ndash;601. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/1745-9133.12213&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/1745-9133.12213&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunshine, J., &amp;amp; Tyler, T. R. (2003). The Role of Procedural Justice and Legitimacy in Shaping Public Support for Policing. &lt;em&gt;Law &amp;amp; Society Review&lt;/em&gt;, 37(3), 513&amp;ndash;548.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tankebe, J. (2013). Viewing Things Differently: The Dimensions of Public Perceptions of Police Legitimacy. &lt;em&gt;Criminology&lt;/em&gt;, 51(1), 103&amp;ndash;135. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1745-9125.2012.00291.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1745-9125.2012.00291.x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tarling, R., &amp;amp; Morris, K. (2010). Reporting crime to the police. &lt;em&gt;The British Journal of Criminology&lt;/em&gt;, 50(3), 474&amp;ndash;490. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/bjc/azqO&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/bjc/azqO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valentine, J. L., Sekula, L. K., Cook, L. J., Campbell, R., Colbert, A., &amp;amp; Weedn, V. W. (2019). Justice Denied: Low Submission Rates of Sexual Assault Kits and the Predicting Variables. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Interpersonal Violence&lt;/em&gt;, 34(17), 3547&amp;ndash;3573. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0886260516681881&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0886260516681881&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van de Schoot, R., &amp;amp; Depaoli, S. (2014). Bayesian analyses: Where to start and what to report. &lt;em&gt;The European Health Psychologist&lt;/em&gt;, 16(2), 75&amp;ndash;84.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watkins, A. (2019). Old rape kits finally got tested. 64 attackers were convicted. In &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/12/nyregion/rape-kit-tests.html&#34;&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/12/nyregion/rape-kit-tests.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wellford, C., &amp;amp; Cronin, J. (1999). An analysis of variables affecting the clearance of homicides: A multistate study. &lt;em&gt;Justice Research and Statistics Association&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://jrsainfo.org/pubs/reports/homicides_report.pdf&#34;&gt;http://jrsainfo.org/pubs/reports/homicides_report.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wells, W. (2016). Some considerations when making decisions about prioritizing sexual assault kits for forensic testing. &lt;em&gt;Criminology and Public Policy&lt;/em&gt;, 15(2), 585&amp;ndash;592. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/1745-9133.12206&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/1745-9133.12206&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wells, W., Fansher, A. K., &amp;amp; Campbell, B. A. (2019). The results of CODIS-hit investigations in a sample of cases with unsubmitted sexual assault kits. &lt;em&gt;Crime &amp;amp; Delinquency&lt;/em&gt;, 65(1), 122&amp;ndash;148. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0011128717732506&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0011128717732506&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ylang, N., &amp;amp; Holtfreter, K. (2019). The Decision to arrest in sexual assault case processing: A test of Black&amp;rsquo;s theory of the behavior of law. &lt;em&gt;Violence Against Women&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1077801219862632&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1077801219862632&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yung, C. R. (2013). How to lie with rape statistics: America&amp;rsquo;s hidden rape crisis. &lt;em&gt;Iowa Law Review&lt;/em&gt;, 99, 1197&amp;ndash;1256.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corresponding author: Scott M. Mourtgos, University of Utah, scott.mourtgos@utah.edu &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Stakes Administrative Discretion: What Drives Body-Worn Camera Activations?</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2021-01-03-high-stakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 19:29:40 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2021-01-03-high-stakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forthcoming (2021), &lt;em&gt;Public Administration Review&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ianadamsresearch.com/pdfs/high-stakes.pdf&#34;&gt;Download a copy of the pre-print here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian T. Adams&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ian.adams@utah.edu&#34;&gt;ian.adams@utah.edu&lt;/a&gt; Department of Political Science, University of Utah
&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott M. Mourtgos &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:scott.mourtgos@utah.edu&#34;&gt;scott.mourtgos@utah.edu&lt;/a&gt; Department of Political Science, University of Utah&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharon H. Mastracci &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sharon.mastracci@poli-sci.utah.edu&#34;&gt;sharon.mastracci@poli-sci.utah.edu&lt;/a&gt; Department of Political Science, University of Utah&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evidence-for-practice&#34;&gt;Evidence for Practice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job functions best explain activations of police BWCs.
Clear-cut agency policy, such as mandating recording all public contacts, arrests, and probable use-of-force, will increase BWC activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officers with sharper levels of concern that BWC&amp;rsquo;s reduce their professional discretion, or expose them to public hatred and outrage, are likely to activate the cameras less often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the extent possible, public safety administrators should adopt model policies on BWC activation and communicate their support for difficult discretionary decision-making by frontline officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly two-thirds of officers activate their camera more often than predicted by the best performing model.
This indicates that BWC policy effectively sets a &amp;ldquo;floor&amp;rdquo; of minimum activation standards and that overall, officers will record more often than required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sergeant&lt;/strong&gt;: Which side do you want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officer&lt;/strong&gt;: Usually, the better-looking girls are on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sergeant&lt;/strong&gt;: The church girls?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officer&lt;/strong&gt;: Yeah, church girls are a little cleaner, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[pause]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officer&lt;/strong&gt;: That&amp;rsquo;s on that body cam already.
I&amp;rsquo;m already in trouble.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been here two minutes.
Nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Body-worn cameras (BWCs) are a workplace surveillance technology, forming the new normal in US policing.
Increasingly adopted internationally, BWCs are now migrating to other public sector contexts, including medical services (Knapton and Walker 2017), public schools (Adams 2020), and public transit (Ariel et al. 2019).
This expansion of BWCs to other public sector contexts is an opportunity to synthesize the BWC literature with public administration scholarship on administrative discretion, to better prepare public managers for BWC implementation challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evidence so far is weighted towards some positive outcomes from BWC adoption (Lum et al. 2019; White and Malm 2020), but in some cases, the lack of effect has raised the question of whether officer discretion in activating the cameras is to blame. There is some evidence that citizens also distrust leaving the decision to activate a BWC in officers&#39; hands (Bromberg, Charbonneau, and Smith 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rialto Study (Ariel, Farrar, and Sutherland 2015) provided first-of-its-kind results indicating a substantial reduction in use-of-force and public complaints when police officers are equipped with BWCs.
The results from Rialto were found to persist well past the initial experimental period, though questions remain about the context of the department and whether there was something &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; about the agency (Sutherland et al. 2017; Gaub and White 2020) that led to large magnitude effects not often seen in other agencies&#39; experience with BWCs.
For example, in 2007 the city council had voted to disband the Rialto Police Department in favor of contracting for police services with the San Bernardino Sheriff&amp;rsquo;s Office (Kelly and Reston 2007). A new chief, Tony Farrar, was hired in 2011, and later was an author and primary investigator in the Rialto Study. These factors may point to a department at a &amp;ldquo;low point,&amp;rdquo; and that the rapid decreases in use-of-force and complaints were at least partially attributable to sources other than BWCs (see Gaub and White 2020 for a broad discussion of agency context and BWCs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some US agencies had begun limited experimenting with BWCs before the Rialto study (Miller and Toliver 2014) for varied but consistent reasons, including improvements to officer safety, reduced civilian complaints, and reduced agency liability (Hyland 2018). The Rialto study&amp;rsquo;s promising results were the subject of high media coverage (Schneider 2018) and highlighted in President Obama&amp;rsquo;s 21st Century Policing report (President&amp;rsquo;s Task Force, 2015), which recommended BWCs across US policing in order to enhance community trust in police. That recommendation was bolstered by federal funding to purchase BWCs for law enforcement agencies (Edwards 2015). Widespread implementation accelerated across the US beginning in 2015, and by 2018 an estimated 64% of large agencies were using BWCs (Nix, Todak, and Tregle 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With wide BWC implementation came expectations of greater transparency and accountability for police actions (Lum et al. 2019; 2020). However, &amp;ldquo;BWCs will have a minimal deterrent effect when officers have broad discretion around activating their cameras&amp;rdquo; (Peterson and Lawrence 2019, 8). If officers deliberately fail to activate their BWCs to avoid their departments and communities&#39; surveillant gaze, then bad behavior will not be deterred. If, however, officers are good stewards of their profession and follow department policies, then job function&amp;ndash;the actual work of an officer, guided by agency policy, assignment, and oversight&amp;mdash;and not individual characteristics of officers or their attitudes about BWCs will predict activations. This article tests competing explanations for the exercise of discretion in policing, a high-stakes context for administrative discretion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;review-of-the-literature-administrative-discretion-and-body-worn-cameras&#34;&gt;Review of the Literature: Administrative Discretion and Body-Worn Cameras&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the purpose of BWCs is to monitor officer behavior, why are cameras not always recording?
Or if cameras must be activated manually, why give the officer discretion over that decision?
Discretion in public decision-making is at once a threat to democracy (Aberbach and Rockman 1988; Finer 1941), a source of social and economic inequality (Cárdenas and Cruz 2017), and yet a fact of administrative life (Sowa and Selden 2003).
Imperfect oversight means that &amp;ldquo;responsible conduct of administrative functions is not so much enforced as it is &lt;em&gt;elicited&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; (Friedrich 1940, 9).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early evidence from a study in Phoenix, Arizona (Katz et al. 2015) found that within a discretionary policy framework, activation rates for BWCs was relatively low, at under 30% overall, and that activation rates declined over time to a low of 13.2% by the end of the study.
This evidence was supported by a one-year study in Mesa, Arizona (Young and Ready 2016), which compared two cohorts of BWC-equipped officers under a mandatory activation policy versus a discretionary policy.
When officers were allowed more discretion, activation rates fell by 27%, though this negative effect was more pronounced for officers who were mandated to wear the cameras compared to those who volunteered to do so.
Further, a multi-site study that included both US and European study sites found that BWCs increased assaults against officers (Ariel et al. 2016b).
The authors returned with further analysis showing that treatment fidelity had been compromised in the original study.
The secondary analysis (Ariel et al. 2017) theorized that unplanned, &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; discretion in some study sites had backfired, leading to increased use-of-force, suggesting that BWC policies should seek some optimal deterrence point that allows for some officer discretion, but with a strong assumption for recording of most police-public interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officers receive training on BWCs and activation guidance (Gaub et al. 2020).
Agency policy determines when and what must and must not be recorded (White and Malm 2020), but in the field (Leys 1943; Simon 1944), it is up to the officer to decide whether to activate their BWC or not.
Procedural controls are only partially effective in curbing discretion (Spence 1999).
At the time of this writing, file storage costs prohibit municipalities from practicing an always-on BWC policy, and remote or automatic camera activation is not yet widespread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Street-level bureaucrats in law enforcement possess the power to use lethal force in the discharge of their duties.
Better understanding what drives BWC activation in a discretionary environment can lead to improved training, policy, and auditing related to BWCs.
Understanding the forces competing for control of an officer&amp;rsquo;s discretion is the first step in structuring theories of controlling that discretion (Mastrofski 2004), and can lead to improved training, policy, and auditing related to BWCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bwc-activations-as-high-stakes-administrative-discretion&#34;&gt;BWC Activations as High-Stakes Administrative Discretion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police work &amp;ldquo;entails a tension between the exercise of discretion by officers on the street and the control of that discretion by police organizations&amp;rdquo; (Engel and Worden 2003, 131).
Understanding officer discretion has been a long-standing concern of researchers (Davis 1975; Goldstein 1963).
Discretion is at the core of the professional police identity (Bayley 2011; Crank 2014), which itself is a primary component of officer performance and wellbeing (Schaible 2018).
Both Wilson (1968) and Bittner (1970) provide foundational explanations for understanding the necessity of police discretion.
Discretion is the necessary leeway granted to police because that is the only reasonable tool to effectively deal with the situational exigencies encountered by police (Bittner 1970).
Early exploration of a theory of street-level bureaucracy (Lipsky 1980) was built atop an attempt to understand police discretion in use-of-force, and how those decisions both imperil and produce justice (Lipsky 1973).
The first systematic study of police shootings (Fyfe 1979) found that officers&#39; discretion could be constrained with policy changes, and Rohr (1989) saw administrative discretion as the critical ethical issue faced by public servants.
Police officers must balance ethical considerations even in non-violent encounters, such as DUI enforcement (Mastrofski, Ritti, and Snipes 1994), and discretionary behavior is tightly coupled with the administrative priorities of the agency (Mastrofski, Ritti, and Hoffmaster 2002).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its value to both the institution of policing and members of the policing profession, discretion is often viewed negatively, as a confounding tendency to undermine agency policy (Tummers and Bekkers 2014) or research designs (Ariel et al. 2016a).
When misused, officer discretion can become a legalistic excuse to perpetuate social inequities.
Thus, &amp;ldquo;while street-level worker judgment is necessary and ever-present, it is fundamentally illegitimate unless operating within specific, juridical bounds&amp;rdquo; (Maynard-Moody and Musheno 2000, S18).
As agencies and communities seek greater control over outcomes, officers&#39; ability to exercise discretion decreases (Shane 2019).
However, with an increase in policy complexity, officers may opt to simply record everything, even in situations where policy encourages the primacy of privacy over evidentiary value (Newell and Greidanus 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failure to activate BWCs can have adverse consequences, particularly in instances of police using lethal force.
Two officers involved in the police killing of Breonna Taylor did not activate their BWCs during the incident, enhancing public anger and leading to both officers being placed on administrative leave (Madani 2020) and intense community concern.
Not all failures to activate are intentional, and technological limitations, the immediacy of some incidents, and unfamiliarity with the technology can lead to otherwise recordable incidents going unrecorded.
While still not widely implemented, fully automatic activations of BWCs could alleviate the question of officer discretion (White and Malm 2020).
However, in jurisdictions with broad public access to police recordings, there are significant questions about the impact on privacy for both police and the public (see Newell and Greidanus 2018, for an early discussion of similar concerns).
The tension between agency control and individual discretion could manifest as the officer&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;failure to activate a BWC limits the potential benefits of the technology,&amp;rdquo; including the presumed positives of increased transparency, legitimacy, and community trust (Lawrence et al. 2019, 1).
Thus, the concern arises: Do officers comply with department policy, or rely on their attitudes towards the cameras in decisions to activate BWCs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bwc-activations-a-principal-agent-problem-or-principled-agents&#34;&gt;BWC Activations: A Principal-Agent Problem, or Principled Agents?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BWC policies vary widely (see White and Malm 2020 for a current review).
Where policies do exist, there are mandatory and prohibited times for activation and a messy middle where officers are granted broad discretion.
For example, most departments mandate activation when use-of-force is expected and prohibit activation where a juvenile victim of a sex crime is interviewed.
But: &amp;ldquo;Three-quarters of policies allow officer discretion in activation, if mandatory and prohibited criteria are not in play&amp;rdquo; (White and Malm 2020, 61).
Making novel use of the metadata contained within BWC footage, Martain, Harinam, and Ariel (2020) analyze over 1.7 million BWC activations from 6333 officers, and found an activation compliance rate of 82.7%.
However, this relatively high number is disproportionately affected by multiple activations at the same call, and the authors show that activation is heterogenous, and 55.7% of officers activated their camera one or fewer times over the course of a year.
We return to this distinction between over- and under-activators later in the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing views of discretion in BWC activation emerge.
First, in the principal-agent literature (Brehm and Gates 1999; Miller 2005), public servants may act according to personal desires and attitudes rather than guided by their &amp;lsquo;principals,&amp;rsquo; the agency, and the community (Bell et al. 2020).
Scholars have applied the principal-agent explanation in policing, with a pessimistic view regarding &amp;ldquo;the ability of rules and supervision to shape officer behavior, citing officer &amp;lsquo;predispositions&amp;rsquo; and the difficulty of observing police activity&amp;rdquo; (Mummolo 2018, 18).
Officers can undermine policy through &amp;ldquo;their ability to turn [BWCs] off or position a partner to block the view-finder frame&amp;rdquo; (Kerrison, Cobbina, and Bender 2018, 281).
Wallace et al. (2018, 486) trace theoretical factors, including &amp;ldquo;motivational issues, increased scrutiny, function creep, and the negative relationship between employee surveillance and counterproductive workplace behavior&amp;rdquo; that may influence officers to be wary of BWCs.
Though Wallace et al. eventually find BWCs do not induce the passivity (de-policing) the researchers focused on, it may be that similar factors shape BWC activation.
That is, a principal-agent perspective predicts officers with cynical attitudes towards BWCs will activate less frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Principled Agent&amp;rsquo; theory argues that principal-agent theory explains the relatively rare instances where public employees chase self-interest to subvert principals&#39; goals.
However, it cannot explain what motivates public employees to &amp;ldquo;perform thankless tasks, go above and beyond the call of duty, and make virtual gifts of their labor even when the rewards for behaving that way are highly uncertain at best&amp;rdquo; (Dilulio 1994, 277).
Likewise, policing research finds weak or non-existent links between officer attitudes and behavioral outcomes: Arrest decisions are not predicted by job satisfaction (Smith and Klein 1983), nor DUI arrests by attitudes about enforcement (Mastrofski, Ritti, and Snipes 1994; Meyers, Heeren, and Hingson 1989).
Officer attitudes towards domestic violence are not linked to domestic violence arrests (Stith 1990), and attitudes fail to predict officers&#39; coercive behavior (Terrill and Mastrofski 2002).
Engel and Worden (2003) find no link between officer attitude and behavior, concluding that department policy and supervision better predict officers&#39; decision-making.
More recently, Mummolo (2018) shows that New York City police officers were responsive to a sudden change in the department&amp;rsquo;s approach to stop-and-frisk, even while some officer attitudes aligned against the policy change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young and Ready (2016, 35) provide BWC activation evidence for the Principled Agent view: &amp;ldquo;When practical, officers will make every effort to activate the on-officer body camera when responding to a call or have any contact with the public.&amp;rdquo; But other research contradicts this result (Lawrence et al. 2019).
In a department mandating recording in 100% of police interactions with the public, activations ranged between 0% and 71.43%, with a mean of 24.99%.
Call type and experience predict activation, and the authors suggest that future research examine officer attitudes towards BWCs, which may &amp;ldquo;influence how an officer uses this technology&amp;rdquo; (Lawrence et al. 2019, 14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;body-worn-camera-research&#34;&gt;Body-Worn Camera Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BWC studies have increased fourteenfold (Lum et al. 2019; White and Malm 2020) in less than a decade.
Many studies have centered on the effects of BWCs on police use-of-force and citizen complaints.
The literature has not coalesced around straightforward answers, however, and the &amp;ldquo;anticipated effects from BWCs have been overestimated&amp;rdquo; (Lum et al. 2019, 20).
While seven of nineteen studies reveal statistically-significant reductions in use-of-force by police officers wearing cameras (White and Malm 2020), none have established a magnitude of effect similar to the Rialto Study (Ariel, Farrar, and Sutherland 2015), and twelve found no reduction in use-of-force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies investigating the impact of BWCs on police use-of-force and other outcomes have not produced clear answers.
The basis for expecting such a change is deterrence theory.
Proponents contend cameras deter officers from engaging in use-of-force: As &amp;ldquo;the degree of deterrence increases, officers are less likely to use force&amp;rdquo; (Ariel et al. 2017, 2).
However, officers do not consider lawful use-of-force to be illegitimate, even while some public opinion diverges from legalistic views (Mourtgos and Adams 2019).
While there may be a deterrent effect on illegitimate and excessive force, that has not been measured in body-camera experiments.
This mismatch may explain why the most extensive experimental study of BWCs, the Washington DC study, did not detect a single statistically-significant effect on any outcome, including use-of-force.
The result prompted the authors to advise &amp;ldquo;we should recalibrate our expectations&amp;rdquo; regarding BWCs (Yokum, Ravishankar, and Coppock 2019, 22).
As BWC research proceeds, White and Malm (2020, 136) predict: &amp;ldquo;Some of those [BWC] stories will be like Rialto&amp;rsquo;s. Some will be like Washington DC&amp;rsquo;s. And most will likely be somewhere in between.&amp;rdquo; Going forward, White and Malm (2020) recommend careful attention be paid to officer attitudes towards BWCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;police-attitudes-towards-bwcs&#34;&gt;Police Attitudes Towards BWCs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lum et al. (2019) identify at least thirty-two articles investigating officer attitudes towards BWCs, up from thirteen studies reviewed four years earlier (Lum et al. 2015).
The officer-attitude literature consistently finds that as officers gain experience with BWCs, their perceptions become more positive despite early skepticism and negativity (Fouche 2014; Gaub et al. 2016; Jennings, Fridell, and Lynch 2014; Snyder, Crow, and Smykla 2019; White, Todak, and Gaub 2018; Todak and Gaub 2019).
Officers may find BWCs useful in public complaint and internal affairs investigations (Fouche 2014; Goetschel and Peha 2017; Owens and Finn 2017; Pelfrey and Keener 2016), evidence collection (Gaub, Todak, and White 2018; White, Todak, and Gaub 2018), and improving job performance (Gramagila and Phillips 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One explanation for officers&#39; negative attitudes is that BWCs curb discretion or impose a hesitancy to use force, even when justified.
Dubbed the &amp;ldquo;over-deterrent&amp;rdquo; effect, this phenomenon has been documented experimentally (Ariel, Sutherland, and Henstock 2018).
Other research links officer attitudes towards BWCs to organizational factors.
Adams and Mastracci (2019b) confirm perceived organizational support mediates burnout experienced by officers equipped with BWCs.
Perceptions of organizational justice also shape BWC attitudes (Kyle and White 2017), though three other studies (Huff, Katz, and Webb 2018; Lawshe et al. 2018; Todak and Gaub 2019) find no link.
Adams and Mastracci (2019a) sidestep whether officers like BWCs and instead construct the Perceived Intensity of Monitoring (PIM) scale, which captures officer perceptions on professional discretion, the capture of personal or embarrassing information by cameras, and the degree to which officer interests are taken into account when releasing footage publicly.
The PIM scale connects to concerns about BWCs by officers, along dimensions of how the technology is perceived to affect them professionally and personally.
In the studied agency, BWCs are mandated, not optional, so preference for wearing one is beside the point, and the PIM scale items represent realistic concerns of officers that may inhibit camera activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;methods-hypotheses-and-data&#34;&gt;Methods, Hypotheses, and Data&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analytic-plan&#34;&gt;Analytic Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an exploratory, hypothesis-generating study of a single agency (Gerring and Cojocaru 2016), interested in explaining what accounts for variation in BWC activations.
Building upon a null model of demographic measures, we separately model the collection of Job Function and Attitudinal measures.
Inter-model reporting allows us to make conclusions about the significance and direction of individual correlates, and confirm or reject the hypotheses developed below.
Intra-model comparisons of model fit, explanatory power, and likelihood statistics further allow for theory building in BWC activation, with the overall goal of litigating between conceptions of officers&#39; BWC activations as principal-agent problems, or principled agents acting as directed by agency policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hypothesis-generation&#34;&gt;Hypothesis Generation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We test three potential theoretical explanations for camera activation: Officer demographics, demands of the job, and attitudes about BWCs.
Previous research provides little specific guidance regarding a connection between officer demographics and BWC activation.
Marvel and Resh (2015) provide some evidence that demographics can shape administrative discretion.
However, mixed findings lead the authors to recommend profession-specific tests of their theoretical guidance, under the general prediction that passive and active representation are strengthened in the context of increased discretion (Sowa and Selden 2003).
In the context of this study, the only minority demographic variable available is sex, with women representing just 6.8% of the sample in a profession that continues to struggle to achieve anything close to sex parity among its employees (Bishu and Headley 2020).
However, there is no clear theoretical or empirical guidance on an expectation that sex would influence BWC activation in a specific direction.
Further conflicting the expectations here is, in the BWC activation context, the appropriate discretionary decision might be to not activate, i.e., in the presence of a victim of a sexual or domestic crime (Adams and Mastracci 2017; Ariel et al. 2017).
Still, given the persistent academic interest in these correlates in relationship to discretionary measures, we include officer sex within the demographic model with no expectation of a directional effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the policing literature, age, sex, and race all consistently connect to police performance outcomes, including use-of-force (Fridell and Lim 2016; Paoline and Terrill 2007), though there is no consistent expectation that these correlates significantly affect BWC activation.
Katz et al. (2015) show a decrease in BWC activations as officers gain experience with the cameras, but Lawrence et al. (2019) find activations increase approximately 25% for every additional fourteen days of BWC experience.
Based on the literature, the following non-directional hypothesis is constructed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Officer demographics (years of experience, sex, rank, and length of BWC experience) affect BWC activations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young and Ready (2016) support the influence of department policy on BWC activation, as does Ariel et al. (2017), who find that supervisor approval to depart from study protocol, effectively granting broad discretion on whether to activate, led to officers failing to activate the cameras.
Agency policies indicate the types of situations in which a BWC recording is expected, which are encountered at varying rates according to an officer&amp;rsquo;s job function and job-related activities.
We address the agency-specific activation policy shortly, but in brief, officers who engage in higher levels of specific job behavior &amp;ndash; taking a primary call, using force, and make arrests, for example &amp;ndash; are expected to activate their cameras more often.
This prediction is a blending of job role and rule following leading to BWC activation.
For our purposes, we test both under the heading of job function with the strong assumption that officers will respond to agency policy (Mummolo 2018).
A second hypothesis predicts variation in officers&#39; BWC activations is due to job functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H2&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Officers with more primary calls, who make more arrests, and are involved in more use-of-force incidents, activate their BWCs more often than officers with less activity in those areas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the importance of discretion in public service (Maynard-Moody, Musheno, and Musheno 2003) and how beliefs, biases, and perceptions affect discretion, are well established (Epp, Maynard-Moody, and Haider-Markel 2014).
Although research on BWC-related attitudes is has grown, regarding activation, somewhat limited guidance is offered.
To examine whether officers represent Principled Agents (Dilulio 1994) or as principal-agent problems, an attitudinal hypothesis is tested:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H3&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Officers with negative attitudes towards body-worn cameras activate their cameras less often than officers with positive attitudes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;survey-and-administrative-data&#34;&gt;Survey and Administrative Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An electronic survey was distributed in Summer 2018, remaining open for 30 days.
Of the 461 officers invited to the survey, 188 completed it, for a response rate of 40.1%.
Of the 188 respondents, 147 are equipped with a BWC.
One of these held a rank higher than lieutenant and was dropped, resulting in a final sample of 146.
Detailed descriptive data for the sample is reported below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Administrative data was not expected or included in the original survey design, but was made available many months after completing the survey effort.
Following the primary investigators&#39; delivery of a white-paper to the agency with the survey results, the relationship between agency administration and the research team strengthened.
While the underlying survey data had already been analyzed for a separate study (Adams and Mastracci 2019a), the opportunity arose to collect matched administrative data, including the dependent variable here, BWC activations.
Thus, some of the underlying attitude items have previously been reported in a peer-reviewed study, though the scalar form, identification, intent, and statistical analysis are different.
In addition to the dependent variable, administrative data were supplied on use-of-force, arrest, and primary dispatched calls.
The administrative data are matched to the same 30-day window of the electronic survey.
Respondents did not know the researchers&#39; intent to combine survey data with department-level reporting on activations, use-of-force, or job function, curbing the risk of demand bias and hypothesis guessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;subject-site-respondents-and-activation-policy&#34;&gt;Subject Site, Respondents, and Activation Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agency was selected as part of a larger study in which the largest corrections agency, sheriff&amp;rsquo;s office, and municipal policing agency (the current case) in the state all simultaneously participated in a large online survey effort of their entire staff.
All three agencies were selected as representatives of US law enforcement&amp;rsquo;s three typical modes, and as the largest agencies in their respective modes.
In Gerring&amp;rsquo;s (2007) case selection framework, the current case is capturing multiple useful dimensions for an exploratory study: it is 1) extreme as represented by its size, 2) an index case representing the first agency to widely adopt BWCs, and 3) most similar to at least forty-nine other US agencies responsible for policing a capital city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviews of the evidence base for BWCs suggest that agency characteristics might be responsible for uneven findings (Gaub and White 2020; White and Malm 2020).
The department is located in a capital city serving a population of more than 200,000 (US Census Bureau 2017).
This department was selected for its widespread, long-standing implementation of BWCs, and its willingness to provide detailed data on use-of-force, BWC activation, and other measures of interest.
The department equips frontline sworn personnel with BWCs for &amp;ldquo;first responder roles,&amp;rdquo; including patrol, motor and bike officers, SWAT, gang, and accident investigators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selected agency was the first in its state to invest significantly in BWCs, deploying 250 cameras by October 2014, well in advance of the wave of BWC adoptions nationwide.
The BWC Scorecard tracker (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bwcscorecard.org&#34;&gt;www.bwcscorecard.org&lt;/a&gt;) finds the agency&amp;rsquo;s BWC policy, 1) is publicly available, 2) strongly limits officer discretion in recording, 3) allows cancellation of recording at the request of the person they are interacting with, but does not require notification of the recording, 4) allows officer review of the footage before completion of a written report, 5) retains footage but does not mandate deletion, 6) prohibits unauthorized copying of the footage, but does not explicitly prohibit tampering or modifying the footage, 7) does not expressly allow for the automatic release of footage to individuals filing complaints, and 8) does not expressly prohibit biometric indexing and searching of footage.
The tracker has not been updated since 2017, but the policy tracker accurately reflects the agency&amp;rsquo;s BWC policy at the time of our data collection.
The scorecard fails to account for some applicable city and state policies which override perceived absences of policy features.
For example, the city has a policy mandating the release of BWC footage related to officer-involved lethal force within two weeks of the incident, and the state has legislative requirements governing the release of public records, including BWC footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of this study, the most important policy feature is that of discretion, and the selected agency has strong constraints on officer discretion in BWC activation, and has strict disciplinary action for failure to activate when required.
Department policy requires officers to activate BWCs when they interact with the public during: 1) All enforcement and investigative contacts, 2) Traffic stops, 3) Self-initiated activity in which the officer would typically notify dispatch (i.e., proactive police work), 4) Any contact that becomes adversarial in a situation that would not otherwise require BWC activation, 5) Any use-of-force; 6) Dispatched calls for service, and 7) Execution of a warrant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, in the presence of a strong policy regarding discretion, activation is predicted to be a function of job functions such as being dispatched as the primary officer on a call.
&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1&lt;/strong&gt; plots the number of primary calls against BWC activations.
These raw data reveal a positive relationship between calls and BWC activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;figure-1-bwc-activations-and-total-primary-calls-by-officer-n146&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1: BWC Activations and Total Primary Calls by Officer (n=146)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/fig1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 1: BWC Activations and Total Primary Calls by Officer (n=146)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants are 146 police officers, all of whom are assigned a BWC, in a single police agency located in the western US.
On average, participants are majority white (71%) and male (93%), approximately 40 years old, with about 13 years of law enforcement experience.
Participants reflect the demographics of police officers nationwide, though with higher educational attainment: 33.9% have bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees, while 10.82% have master&amp;rsquo;s degrees or higher.
Approximately 10% report less than a year of experience wearing BWCs, while 56% have more than three years of experience wearing BWCs.
Descriptive statistics are in &lt;strong&gt;Table 1&lt;/strong&gt;, and variable operationalization is found in the appendix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;table-1-descriptive-statistics-for-study-measures&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 1. Descriptive Statistics for Study Measures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Variable&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;n&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mean&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Std. Dev.&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Min&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Max&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dependent Variable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;ln&lt;/em&gt;(BWC Activations)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.42&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demographic Measures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sex&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Female&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Male&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;136&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Years LEO Experience&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13.01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.320&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;How Long Worn BWC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rank&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Officer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;115&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sergeant&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lieutenant&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Function Measures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Use-of-Force Count&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Total Primary Calls&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40.68&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;38.49&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;205&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Arrests&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.55&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Front-line Officer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.84&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BWC Attitude Measures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Freedom&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.83&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Decision&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.83&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Manipulate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.88&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.78&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Modify&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Embarrass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.97&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.61&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Hatred&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.05&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Fair&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Protect&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.55&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Wellbeing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.47&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;measurement&#34;&gt;Measurement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distribution of activations among 146 officers ranges between zero and 198 (x̄=58.05, SD=46.82).
Approximately 25% of the sample had eleven or fewer activations during the study period, and thirteen officers (8.90%) had zero. Because of the highly-skewed distribution in the raw count, a natural log of the raw count plus one (to account for zeroes) is used (x̄=3.42, SD=1.51).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jennings et al. (2014) suggest veteran officers hold differing views regarding BWCs compared to more junior colleagues, and so years of experience is reported (x̄=13.01, SD=7.32). If it is true that officers with positive attitudes towards BWCs are more likely to use the camera, and those attitudes improve with time (Gaub et al. 2016), then officers with more BWC experience should have more BWC activations. This temporal effect is operationalized with a five-point scale which asks an officer how long they have worn a BWC: (1) less than six months, (2) up to a year (3) up to two years (4) up to three years, and (5) over three years (x̄=4.21, SD=1.10). There may be differences in use-of-force, rank, and job roles between male and female officers (Rabe-Hemp 2017), so we control for sex with a dichotomous indicator for female officers, who comprise 6.85% of the sample. Officer rank is also provided, with 78.77% of participants holding the rank of officer, while those at sergeant comprise 17.12% of the sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;job-function-model&#34;&gt;Job Function Model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job function measures include use-of-force, which is modeled as a count variable between zero and three.
The limited range and high skewness of the use-of-force count align with research establishing any use-of-force as a rare occurrence (Alpert and Dunham 2004). The Use-of-Force measure ranges up to three (x̄=0.32, SD=0.63) and is heavily skewed towards zero, with 75.34% of respondents having no use-of-force incidents during the study period. The count combines use-of-force incidents from across the spectrum, including pepper spray (OC), Taser deployments, physical strikes, and firearm pointing. There were no firearm uses or deadly force incidents by officers during the study period. Total Primary Calls measure how many calls an officer is recorded as the primary, documenting officer, and includes both dispatched and proactive cases (x̄=40.68, SD=38.49). A minority of police calls result in either physical or citation arrest. Due to data limitations, only physical arrests are collected as another measure of job activity (x̄=1.56, SD=2.59). During the study period, arrests range up to seventeen, while 57.53% of respondents had zero custodial arrests. Officers with frontline, patrol, and street-investigation assignments (84.93% of the sample) are expected to activate their BWCs more often than those with more administrative or office-centered assignments, and is modeled with the dichotomous dummy measure Front-Line Assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;attitude-measures&#34;&gt;Attitude Measures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kyle and White (2017, 79) propose that &amp;ldquo;officer attitudes regarding BWCs may in fact be a multi-dimensional concept.&amp;rdquo; Therefore, data are gathered on three conceptions of officer attitude that could affect BWC activations. Attitude measures are drawn from the Perceived Intensity of Monitoring (PIM) scale (Adams and Mastracci 2019b), and are reported using a seven-point Likert-like scale, strongly disagree (1) to strongly agree (7).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four measures form the PIM scale&amp;rsquo;s discretion subscale: BWC freedom, BWC decision, BWC manipulate, and BWC modify. These items attempt to measure how &amp;ldquo;officers themselves perceive the impact of BWCs on their discretionary decision making&amp;rdquo; while working (Adams and Mastracci 2019b, 4). Three variables, BWC Fair, BWC Protect, and BWC Wellbeing, form the distribution subscale, and capture how officers perceive BWC footage distribution practices at their department. Are the distribution policies fair? Does the agency protect officers when releasing footage? Does the agency take the officer&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing into account when deciding what to release and how to release it?
The final two attitude measures are aimed at capturing how officers perceive BWCs could impact them personally. BWC Embarrass measures an officer&amp;rsquo;s perception that the cameras could capture potentially embarrassing personal information or incidents. BWC Hatred measures whether officers believe that BWC footage could make them the target of public hate or anger. Both the embarrass and hatred measures are illustrated in the incident from which the opening vignette was drawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results of the log-linear regressions for the null model and two comparison models are presented in &lt;strong&gt;Table 2&lt;/strong&gt;. The results of the model comparisons support the importance of agency policy on BWC activations in leveraging the use of the technology, even in the face of some officers&#39; negative personal perceptions and preferences regarding it. Findings confirm and build upon results from previous research on activations (Lawrence et al. 2019; Young and Ready 2016). A post-hoc, observed power analysis was conducted alongside sensitivity and effect size analyses. Those analyses found the study was well-powered, with small to intermediate effect sizes. Readers can find detailed power and sensitivity analyses in the appendix to this study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;table-2-log-linear-regressions-results-for-bwc-activations-n146&#34;&gt;Table 2. Log-Linear Regressions Results for BWC Activations (n=146)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Demographic (Null Model)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Job Function (Principled Agent)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Attitude (Principle-Agent)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(Intercept)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.803*** (0.492)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.390** (0.507)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.727*** (0.778)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Years LEO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.049** (0.018)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.028 (0.015)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.055** (0.019)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Female&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.269 (0.466)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.286 (0.381)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.234 (0.461)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sergeant&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.474 (0.339)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.222 (0.291)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.160 (0.348)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lieutenant&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-1.685** (0.615)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.655 (0.506)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-1.749** (0.609)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;How long worn BWC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.092 (0.109)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.133 (0.089)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.122 (0.110)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Use-of-Force Count&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.338* (0.159)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Total Calls&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.014*** (0.003)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Total Arrests&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.102* (0.046)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Frontline Assignment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.116*** (0.274)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Freedom&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.047 (0.109)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Decision&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.018 (0.093)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Manipulate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.070 (0.123)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Modify&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.246* (0.098)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Embarrass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.161* (0.081)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Hatred&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.267*** (0.079)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Fair&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.056 (0.128)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Protect&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.055 (0.121)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BWC Wellbeing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.017 (0.147)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.158&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.482&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.289&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Adj.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.128&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.448&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.213&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AIC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;522.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;459.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;516.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BIC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;543.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;492.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;563.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Log. Likelihood&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-254.465&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-218.933&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-242.103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H1&lt;/strong&gt; is rejected, which predicts that individual professional and demographic characteristics will predict BWC activation. The first model explains about one-sixth of the variance in BWC activation.
Sex, and length of time wearing a BWC, are both non-significant. The effect of years of experience is negative and significant. Rank is significant at only the level of lieutenant, and its effect is negative. Officers of command rank such as lieutenant represent a small portion of police officers overall, with only six in this sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, when other factors are held constant, the length of time an officer has worn a BWC is not significantly related to how often they activate the camera, contrasting with previous attitude research suggesting a temporal effect on officer attitudes towards BWCs. While this study does not measure a temporal change in attitude, experience with BWCs is expected to positively influence activations.
The impact of experience with BWCs reported here is in the positive direction but is non-significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robust support is found for &lt;strong&gt;H2&lt;/strong&gt;, which predicts job function covariates will be significantly related to BWC activation. The model explains nearly half of the variance in BWC activation across 146 officers.
Regarding the individual predictors, the effect of force count, primary calls, arrests, and line officer condition are all positive and significant. These correlates, derived from the agency&amp;rsquo;s policy on activations, are all in the direction predicted by policy constraints. For example, the policy requires activation in the event of an arrest, and so the more arrests an officer makes, the more activations expected. This relationship holds for all job function model predictors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H3&lt;/strong&gt; posits that individual officer attitudes regarding BWCs have a significant effect on BWC activations. Minimal support is found for the effect of officers&#39; attitudes towards BWCs, as statistical significance is only observed for one-third of attitudinal correlates, and explaining about one-fifth of activation variance. Regarding the individual predictors, the effect of BWC Modify and BWC Hatred is negative and significant, and the effect of BWC Embarrass is positive and significant. All other attitudinal correlates were non-significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discretion is measured using the survey item: &amp;ldquo;Wearing a body camera pressures me to modify certain professional practices I have had in the past.&amp;rdquo; Previous scholars have revealed that negative attitudes about BWCs stem from officer concerns about the suppressive effects of BWCs on their exercise of professional discretion (Gaub et al. 2016; Gaub, Todak, and White 2018; Headley, Guerette, and Shariati 2017; White, Todak, and Gaub 2018). Our results support those findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimal correlation was found among most study correlates. Moderate correlation is found among attitudinal factors drawn from the same PIM subscales. All correlations are well below the 0.80 threshold (Berry et al. 1985), and findings were robust to adding or dropping predictor variables with moderate correlation. Post-estimation diagnostics show all models are free from impairing multicollinearity, with generalized mean variance inflation factors (GVIF) below the standard cutoff (Fox and Monette 1992). As a general robustness check, an alternative attitude model was constructed, with individual subscale items mutated into latent constructions of &amp;ldquo;discretion&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;distribution.&amp;rdquo; Neither latent variable was statistically significant, though the overall model results are broadly the same, suggesting the original model construction is more acceptable, as it allows the individual items to attain significance (or not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussion&#34;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article investigated three explanations of police officer activation of body-worn cameras: Individual demographic characteristics, individual attitudes towards BWCs, and job function indicators.
Results indicate that job function explains variation in BWC activation, implying that officers are Principled Agents (Dilulio 1994). This is consistent with the bulk of literature that finds, &amp;ldquo;Officers&#39; behavior is only weakly related, if at all, to their occupational attitudes&amp;rdquo; (Engel and Worden 2003, 156).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of an officer&amp;rsquo;s attitudes towards BWCs or their demographic characteristics, our study finds minimal evidence of an impact on how BWCs are used. Results support Dilulio&amp;rsquo;s (1994, 316) conclusion that public service workers are more constrained by agency policy and leadership than motivated by self-interest, because &amp;ldquo;there is more self-sacrifice, and less self-interest, than rational choice theory allows.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing three model specifications indicates that job function correlates provide a better model.
First, in both AIC (job function=459.867; attitudes=516.207) and BIC (job function=492.687; attitudes=563.944) for model selection, the job function model is preferred (Burnham and Anderson 2004).
Further, gains in the amount of variation explained (over the demographic model) are stark.
The job function model gains .320 over the null model with an adjusted R2 of .448, while the attitudes model gains only .085 over the null model with an adjusted R2 of .213. The strong relationship between primary calls, arrests, and use-of-force is visualized in Figure 2, with the addition of a loess-smoothed relationship line between primary calls and activations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;figure-2-scatterplot-of-bwc-activations-by-primary-calls-with-arrests-and-force-count&#34;&gt;Figure 2: Scatterplot of BWC Activations by Primary Calls, with Arrests and Force Count&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/fig2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 2: Scatterplot of BWC Activations by Primary Calls, with Arrests and Force Count&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When assessing model fit, one further factor relates to number rather than magnitude: Are more officers over- or under-activating BWCs compared to the model predictions?
In any OLS regression, the sum of the positive and negative residuals cancels out, but this does not enhance our understanding of whether individual officers are using their camera more or less often than model predictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrasting the number of observations with positive versus negative y residuals shows that 92 officers (63%) activate their cameras more often than predicted, while 54 (37%) activate less often.
This is an important finding and holds for the attitudes model as well (94 officers versus 52).
In terms of unexplained variation, nearly two-thirds of officers activate their cameras more often than predicted by their job functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This result suggests a substantial majority of officers, rather than finding ways not to record, are recording more often than predicted, given the correlates and theory available. This builds upon recent evidence that there is a cohort of officers who have distinct under-activation patters (Martain, Harinam, and Ariel 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top-line finding of this article is that job functions strongly predict BWC activation, explaining nearly half of the variation among officers. This result confirms empirical findings from previous work showing the impact of administrative policy on BWC activations (Young and Ready 2016) and the suspicion from Lum and colleagues (2019, 19) that equivocal empirical results from experiments might arise at least partly from &amp;ldquo;variation in agency policies regarding how the devices should be used.&amp;rdquo; Variation in BWC activation is expected across differing policing contexts because there is variation in the department policies, not due to differences in individual officer perceptions of the technology itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations-and-future-research&#34;&gt;Limitations and Future Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As policies regarding BWCs still evolve, this article&amp;rsquo;s results should be contextualized within its limitations. First, with its cross-sectional design, the study is vulnerable to non-response bias, confounding effects, and item missingness. While the study has a healthy response rate of 49%, it is possible officers who chose not to respond to the survey have a non-random reason for not responding, which might relate to BWC activations and could bias the reported results. Even with a responsive sample, this is a study that relies on a relatively limited one. The size of the sample cuts in two directions, limiting confidence in the effect size estimates while simultaneously increasing the odds of a Type II error. While no statistically significant relationship between some variables is found, this should be considered suggestive but not conclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relatedly, while both the job function model and the supported model report adjusted R2 statistics of close to 0.5, a confounding unmeasured variable cannot be discounted from any cross-sectional study, and caution in interpreting the results outside of the study context is warranted. Finally, law enforcement is a challenging population to survey (Nix et al. 2019), and distrust of academia may dampen respondents&#39; willingness to answer personal and sensitive questions. For example, the average missingness for demographic items here was 18.51%. Future police surveys should consider methods to improve overall responsiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In line with the research questions motivated by Young and Ready&amp;rsquo;s findings (2016), this article provides empirical evidence that factors outside personal attitudes provide the most explanatory power for understanding BWC activations. However, policy direction necessarily relies on appropriate department policy. The studied department implements a BWC policy with a practical bias towards recording interactions between officers and the public. In the context of BWC studies, the policy would be considered a &amp;ldquo;mandatory activation&amp;rdquo; one, as opposed to &amp;ldquo;discretionary activation&amp;rdquo; (White and Malm 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The studied agency has a robust review and compliance scheme, which may influence our findings.
During the time between implementing BWCs in 2014 and this study, the department&amp;rsquo;s command staff estimate fewer than five sustained allegations involving an officer failing to activate a BWC when they should have. High compliance in BWC activation suggests officers are responsive to agency policy (Mummolo 2018), and underlines the importance of accountability procedures as a constraint on officer discretion (Walker 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The studied agency employs all three types of BWC review identified by White and Malm (2020), such that supervisors can audit BWC compliance for administrative, compliance, and performance review. Thus, generalizing this article&amp;rsquo;s findings to departments with more discretionary policies, significantly higher activation non-compliance, or lax supervisor auditing is not recommended until further research can establish replicability in those settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agency context and experience should also be weighed. Within our sample, 75% of officers did not use force during the 30-day study period, and over half did not record a physical arrest. These are measures with high variability between agencies, and suggests even more caution and further study before generalizing to other agencies. Finally, as new evidence shows that &amp;ldquo;under-activators&amp;rdquo; may be comprised of specific types of officers (Martain, Harinam, and Ariel 2020), future research should consider using experimental techniques to provide targeted feedback to these officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third limitation is in the operationalization of the dependent variable. Like many police performance questions (Shane 2019; 2007), the measurement of BWC activation is complex, can support different operationalizations, and lacks research consensus. This challenge across the BWC literature has led to calls for more standardized metrics (White and Malm 2020), and we join that recommendation. It is theoretically possible, albeit technically infeasible, to establish a ratio rather than a count variable to measure BWC activation. In such a design counter-factual, researchers establish a denominator of how often a BWC &lt;em&gt;ought to have been&lt;/em&gt; activated. In practice, however, this is a fundamentally implausible goal for research at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first challenge to the reliable construction of such a denominator is the nature of police work itself. Officers work in chaotic, fluid environments. While a policy may control for many contextual decisions&amp;mdash;activate when force is expected to be used, and during arrests, but not in hospitals or when interviewing the victim of sexual assault (Adams and Mastracci 2017)&amp;mdash;no policy can predict all situations all the time. This may partly explain the negative relationship between activations and officer perception regarding the impact of BWCs on professional discretion. However, policies that grant any level of discretion to officers in BWC activation neatly confound researcher intent to measure how often a camera should have been activated. While such a count might be created by a researcher observing a single officer in a single shift, larger-scale quantitative analysis does not allow for establishing a basic definition for such a denominator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We accept that there are alternative identification methods available, though we argue they have at least as many shortcomings as our selected method. For example, one can imagine constructing a rate of activation (activations per ten calls) in order to introduce some control for opportunity, and identifying the rest of the models as already done. In our view, for an exploratory, hypothesis-generating study, this identification strategy leans too heavily on the assumption that it is officers responding as the primary responder to a call (as opposed to a secondary or tertiary officer) driving activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The empirical data in our sample offer opposing evidence to this, even before modeling decisions.
For example, many observations record far more activations than primary calls, and while the median activations per call is only 1.47, ten officers have over ten activations per primary call. This suggests that job role, not mere call opportunity, is more salient, as officers in patrol specialties are expected to have different attitudes and use for BWCs (Gaub, Todak, and White 2018), and are more likely to be responding as non-primary officers to incidents in order to provide their support as specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, the same motivation for controlling for exposure applies to arrests, or use of force incidents, in that those too provide opportunity for activation. The modeling strategy selected here is not ideal, but appropriate to the study aims of exploring a case with sufficient attributes to allow for hypothesis generation and testing of correlates thought to be salient to BWC activation specifically, and discretion broadly. Future research should consider following recent innovations in BWC research, using metadata to develop more granular datasets capable of confronting the challenges above (Martain, Harinam, and Ariel 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given these challenges, this article adopts a course measure of nuanced performance, and constructs a series of models that attempt to capture the intended benefits of an accurate denominator through inference. The benefits of an accurate denominator should not be forgone, and active work in this area continues at academic and practitioner levels. Here, we demonstrate that through accurate measures of the number of calls, involvement in use-of-force situations, the number of arrests, experience level, and job assignment, one can form adequate proxies for the variables likely to influence how often a BWC ought to have activated. Still, a mix of proxy measures is not the idealized measure itself, and imposes limits on interpreting the findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article opened with a vignette of an officer in Spokane, Washington, who activated his BWC and was thereafter exposed to intense media, political, and public scrutiny (Shanks 2020). Left out of those discussions was the question of why? Why would an officer activate his camera and then immediately be caught saying something he knew would attract criticism?This article suggests the officer activated his BWC because he was supposed to. He was arriving to work a protest, and his department requires BWC activation in that job function. As a Principled Agent, he complied with that policy requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results reported here support straightforward reasoning for why officers activate, or do not activate, their BWCs. Neither underlying demographic characteristics nor variation in attitudes towards BWCs adequately explains how often an officer activates their BWC. Instead, officers use BWCs because agency policy requires them to do so while handling calls, making arrests, and using force. When it comes to BWC activations, officers act as principled agents, not principal-agent problems. This article confirms a long research line that finds weak or absent links between officer attitude and behavior. Officers are responsive to department directives (Mummolo 2018), and as we show, variation in BWC activation is most explainable by variation in job function activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there continue to be no easy answers to explain the mixed results from BWC research overall, this article contributes to the literature by providing preliminary evidence that the failure to capture the cameras&#39; intended benefits does not fall solely on the shoulders of individual officers. As noted in other works (Epp, Maynard-Moody, and Haider-Markel 2014; S. Maynard-Moody and Musheno 2012), the impacts of officer discretion are nuanced. While individual officer behavior is better explained by agency policy and legal guidance than by individual attitude and bias, the policies themselves can perpetuate inequity, and the juridical bounds may grant so much latitude that they &amp;ldquo;take on the nature of a farce&amp;rdquo; (Maynard-Moody and Musheno 2012, S18). It is contingent upon the still-developing guidance for best practices related to the deployment of BWCs to provide proper guidance to the officers equipped with them. The evidence presented here suggests that officers will implement such policy as principled agents of their community and agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\newpage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberbach, Joel D., and Bert A. Rockman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mandates or Mandarins? Control and Discretion in the Modern Administrative State.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review 48 (2): 606&amp;ndash;12. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/975761&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/975761&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adams, Ian T., and Sharon H. Mastracci.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Visibility Is a Trap: The Ethics of Police Body-Worn Cameras and Control.&amp;rdquo; Administrative Theory &amp;amp; Praxis 39 (4): 313&amp;ndash;328. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/10841806.2017.1381482&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/10841806.2017.1381482&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.
2019a.
&amp;ldquo;Police Body-Worn Cameras: Development of the Perceived Intensity of Monitoring Scale.&amp;rdquo; Criminal Justice Review 44 (3): 386&amp;ndash;405.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0734016819846219&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0734016819846219&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.
2019b.
&amp;ldquo;Police Body-Worn Cameras: Effects on Officers&#39; Burnout and Perceived Organizational Support.&amp;rdquo; Police Quarterly 22 (1): 5&amp;ndash;30.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1098611118783987&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1098611118783987&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adams, Richard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Schools Trial Body Cameras to Aid Safety and Monitor Behaviour.&amp;rdquo; The Guardian, February 7, 2020, sec. Education. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/education/2020/feb/07/schools-trial-body-cameras-to-aid-safety-and-monitor-behaviour&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/education/2020/feb/07/schools-trial-body-cameras-to-aid-safety-and-monitor-behaviour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ariel, Barak, William A. Farrar, and Alex Sutherland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Effect of Police Body-Worn Cameras on Use of Force and Citizens&#39; Complaints against the Police: A Randomized Controlled Trial.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Quantitative Criminology 31 (3): 509&amp;ndash;35.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ariel, Barak, Mark Newton, Lorna McEwan, Garry A. Ashbridge, Cristobal Weinborn, and Hagit Sabo Brants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Reducing Assaults Against Staff Using Body-Worn Cameras (BWCs) in Railway Stations.&amp;rdquo; Criminal Justice Review 44 (1): 76&amp;ndash;93.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ariel, Barak, Alex Sutherland, and Darren Henstock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Paradoxical Effects of Self-Awareness of Being Observed: Testing the Effect of Police Body-Worn Cameras on Assaults and Aggression against Officers.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Experimental Criminology 14 (1): 19&amp;ndash;47.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ariel, Barak, Alex Sutherland, Darren Henstock, Josh Young, Paul Drover, Jayne Sykes, Simon Megicks, and Ryan Henderson.
2016a.
&amp;ldquo;Report: Increases in Police Use of Force in the Presence of Body-Worn Cameras Are Driven by Officer Discretion: A Protocol-Based Subgroup Analysis of Ten Randomized Experiments.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Experimental Criminology 12 (3): 453&amp;ndash;463.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.
2016b.
&amp;ldquo;Wearing Body Cameras Increases Assaults against Officers and Does Not Reduce Police Use of Force: Results from a Global Multi-Site Experiment.&amp;rdquo; European Journal of Criminology 13 (6): 744&amp;ndash;755.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ariel, Barak, Alex Sutherland, Darren Henstock, Josh Young, and Gabriela Sosinski.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Deterrence Spectrum: Explaining Why Police Body-Worn Cameras &amp;lsquo;Work&amp;rsquo;or &amp;lsquo;Backfire&amp;rsquo;in Aggressive Police&amp;ndash;Public Encounters.&amp;rdquo; Policing: A Journal of Policy and Practice 12 (1): 6&amp;ndash;26.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayley, David H.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Et Tu Brute: Are Police Agencies Managed Better or Worse than Universities?&amp;rdquo; Police Practice and Research 12 (4): 313&amp;ndash;316.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bell, Elizabeth, Ani Ter Mkrtchyan, Wesley Wehde, and Kylie Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just or Unjust? How Ideological Beliefs Shape Street-Level Bureaucrats&amp;rsquo; Perceptions of Administrative Burden.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review n/a (n/a). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/puar.13311&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/puar.13311&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berry, William D., William D. Berry, Stanley Feldman, and Dr Stanley Feldman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Regression in Practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bishu, Sebawit G., and Andrea M. Headley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Equal Employment Opportunity: Women Bureaucrats in Male-Dominated Professions.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review n/a (n/a). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/puar.13178&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/puar.13178&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bittner, Egon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Functions of Police in Modern Society. Washington, DC: US National Institute of Mental Health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brehm, John O., and Scott Gates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working, Shirking, and Sabotage: Bureaucratic Response to a Democratic Public. University of Michigan Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bromberg, Daniel E., Étienne Charbonneau, and Andrew Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Body‐Worn Cameras and Policing: A List Experiment of Citizen Overt and True Support.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review 78 (6): 883&amp;ndash;91. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/puar.12924&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/puar.12924&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnham, Kenneth P., and David R. Anderson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Multimodel Inference: Understanding AIC and BIC in Model Selection.&amp;rdquo; Sociological Methods &amp;amp; Research 33 (2): 261&amp;ndash;304. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0049124104268644&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0049124104268644&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cárdenas, Sergio, and Edgar E. Ramírez de la Cruz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Controlling Administrative Discretion Promotes Social Equity? Evidence from a Natural Experiment.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review 77 (1): 80&amp;ndash;89. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/puar.12590&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/puar.12590&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crank, John P. 2014.
Understanding Police Culture.
New York: Routledge.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315721255&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315721255&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davis, Kenneth Culp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Police Discretion. West Publishing Company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dilulio Jr, John D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Principled Agents: The Cultural Bases of Behavior in a Federal Government Bureaucracy.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory 4 (3): 277&amp;ndash;318.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edwards, Julia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Obama Administration Says to Provide $20 Million for Police Body Cameras.&amp;rdquo; Reuters, May 1, 2015. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-police-cameras-idUSKBN0NM3PL20150501&#34;&gt;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-police-cameras-idUSKBN0NM3PL20150501&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engel, Robin Shepard, and Robert E. Worden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;POLICE OFFICERS&amp;rsquo;ATTITUDES, BEHAVIOR, AND SUPERVISORY INFLUENCES: AN ANALYSIS OF PROBLEM SOLVING.&amp;rdquo; Criminology 41 (1): 131&amp;ndash;166.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epp, Charles R., Steven Maynard-Moody, and Donald P. Haider-Markel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pulled over: How Police Stops Define Race and Citizenship. Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finer, Herman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Administrative Responsibility in Democratic Government.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review 1 (4): 335&amp;ndash;50. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/972907&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/972907&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fouche, Adam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Officer Attitudes on Deployment of Body-Worn Cameras in the University of Georgia Police Department Patrol Division.&amp;rdquo; Campus Law Enforcement Journal 44 (3): 21&amp;ndash;28.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fox, John, and Georges Monette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Generalized Collinearity Diagnostics.&amp;rdquo; Journal of the American Statistical Association 87 (417): 178&amp;ndash;83. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/01621459.1992.10475190&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/01621459.1992.10475190&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fridell, Lorie, and Hyeyoung Lim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Assessing the Racial Aspects of Police Force Using the Implicit-and Counter-Bias Perspectives.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Criminal Justice 44: 36&amp;ndash;48.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friedrich, Carl J.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Public Policy and the Nature of Administrative Responsibility.&amp;rdquo; In Public Policy, 3&amp;ndash;24. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fyfe, James J.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Administrative Interventions on Police Shooting Discretion: An Empirical Examination.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Criminal Justice 7 (4): 309&amp;ndash;23.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaub, Janne E., David E. Choate, Natalie Todak, Charles M. Katz, and Michael D. White.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Officer Perceptions of Body-Worn Cameras before and after Deployment: A Study of Three Departments.&amp;rdquo; Police Quarterly 19 (3): 275&amp;ndash;302.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaub, Janne E., Natalie Todak, and Michael D. White.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;One Size Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Fit All: The Deployment of Police Body-Worn Cameras to Specialty Units.&amp;rdquo; International Criminal Justice Review, 1057567718789237.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaub, Janne E., and Michael D. White.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Open to Interpretation: Confronting the Challenges of Understanding the Current State of Body-Worn Camera Research.&amp;rdquo; American Journal of Criminal Justice, January. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s12103-020-09518-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s12103-020-09518-4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaub, Janne E., Michael D. White, and Aili Malm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;An Examination of the Type, Scope, and Duration of Body-Worn Camera Training.&amp;rdquo; Tempe, AZ: Arizona State University Center for Violence Prevention and Community Safety.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gerring, John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Case Study Research: Principles and Practices. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press. Gerring, John, and Lee Cojocaru.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Selecting Cases for Intensive Analysis: A Diversity of Goals and Methods.&amp;rdquo; Sociological Methods &amp;amp; Research 45 (3): 392&amp;ndash;423. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0049124116631692&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0049124116631692&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goetschel, Max, and Jon M. Peha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police Perceptions of Body-Worn Cameras.&amp;rdquo; American Journal of Criminal Justice 42 (4): 698&amp;ndash;726.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldstein, Herman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police Discretion: The Ideal versus the Real.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review, 140&amp;ndash;148.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gramagila, Joseph A., and Scott W. Phillips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police Officers&amp;rsquo; Perceptions of Body-Worn Cameras in Buffalo and Rochester.&amp;rdquo; American Journal of Criminal Justice, 1&amp;ndash;16.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headley, Andrea M., Rob T. Guerette, and Auzeen Shariati.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A Field Experiment of the Impact of Body-Worn Cameras (BWCs) on Police Officer Behavior and Perceptions.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Criminal Justice 53 (November): 102&amp;ndash;9. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcrimjus.2017.10.003&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcrimjus.2017.10.003&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huff, Jessica, Charles M. Katz, and Vincent J. Webb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Understanding Police Officer Resistance to Body-Worn Cameras.&amp;rdquo; Policing: An International Journal 41 (4): 482&amp;ndash;495.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyland, Shelley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Body-Worn Cameras in Law Enforcement Agencies, 2016.&amp;rdquo; Bureau of Justice Statistics. November 2018. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bjs.gov/index.cfm?ty=pbdetail&amp;amp;iid=6426&#34;&gt;https://www.bjs.gov/index.cfm?ty=pbdetail&amp;amp;iid=6426&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jennings, Wesley G., Lorie A. Fridell, and Mathew D. Lynch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cops and Cameras: Officer Perceptions of the Use of Body-Worn Cameras in Law Enforcement.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Criminal Justice 42 (6): 549&amp;ndash;556.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katz, Charles M., Mike Kurtenbach, David E. Choate, and Michael D. White.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Phoenix, Arizona, Smart Policing Initiative: Evaluating the Impact of Police Officer Body-Worn Cameras.&amp;rdquo; Washington, D.C.: Bureau of Justice Assistance, US Department of Justice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kelly, David, and Maeve Reston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Rialto Officer&amp;rsquo;s Death a Blow to a Police Force on the Rebound.&amp;rdquo; Los Angeles Times, October 20, 2007. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-2007-oct-20-me-rialto20-story.html&#34;&gt;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-2007-oct-20-me-rialto20-story.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kerrison, Erin M., Jennifer Cobbina, and Kimberly Bender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stop-Gaps, Lip Service, and the Perceived Futility of Body-Worn Police Officer Cameras in Baltimore City.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Ethnic &amp;amp; Cultural Diversity in Social Work, 1&amp;ndash;18.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knapton, Sarah, and Peter Walker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Doctors and Nurses Could Be Issued with Body Cameras to Record Violent Patients.&amp;rdquo; The Telegraph, May 5, 2017. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/science/2017/05/05/doctors-nurses-could-issued-on-body-cameras-record-violent-patients/&#34;&gt;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/science/2017/05/05/doctors-nurses-could-issued-on-body-cameras-record-violent-patients/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kyle, Michael J., and David R. White.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Impact of Law Enforcement Officer Perceptions of Organizational Justice on Their Attitudes Regarding Body-Worn Cameras.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Crime and Justice 40 (1): 68&amp;ndash;83.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawrence, Daniel S., David McClure, Aili Malm, Mathew Lynch, and Nancy La Vigne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Activation of Body-Worn Cameras: Variation by Officer, Over Time, and by Policing Activity.&amp;rdquo; Criminal Justice Review 44 (3): 339&amp;ndash;55. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0734016819846228&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0734016819846228&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawshe, Nathan L., George W. Burruss, Matthew J. Giblin, and Joseph A. Schafer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Behind the Lens: Police Attitudes toward Body-Worn Cameras and Organizational Justice.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Crime and Justice, 1&amp;ndash;20.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leys, Wayne A. R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ethics and Administrative Discretion.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review 3 (1): 10&amp;ndash;23. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/973098&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/973098&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lipsky, Michael.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Law and Order: Police Encounters. Transaction Publishers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Street-Level Bureaucracy: The Critical Role of Street-Level Bureaucrats.&amp;rdquo; Classics of Public Administration 7: 362&amp;ndash;369.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lum, Cynthia, Christopher S. Koper, David B. Wilson, Megan Stoltz, Michael Goodier, Elizabeth Eggins, Angela Higginson, and Lorraine Mazerolle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Body-Worn Cameras&#39; Effects on Police Officers and Citizen Behavior: A Systematic Review.&amp;rdquo; Campbell Systematic Reviews 16 (3): e1112.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lum, Cynthia M., Christopher S. Koper, Linda M. Merola, Amber Scherer, and Amanda Reioux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Existing and Ongoing Body Worn Camera Research: Knowledge Gaps and Opportunities.&amp;rdquo; George Mason University. &lt;a href=&#34;http://cebcp.org/wp-content/technology/BodyWornCameraResearch.pdf&#34;&gt;http://cebcp.org/wp-content/technology/BodyWornCameraResearch.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lum, Cynthia, Megan Stoltz, Christopher S. Koper, and J.
Amber Scherer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Research on Body-Worn Cameras: What We Know, What We Need to Know.&amp;rdquo; Criminology &amp;amp; Public Policy 18 (1): 93&amp;ndash;118.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Madani, Doha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Louisville Police Chief Fired after Officer Bodycams Found to Be off during Fatal Shooting.&amp;rdquo; NBC News, June 1, 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/louisville-police-chief-fired-after-officer-bodycams-found-be-during-n1221351&#34;&gt;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/louisville-police-chief-fired-after-officer-bodycams-found-be-during-n1221351&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martain, Ben R, Vincent Harinam, and Barak Ariel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Linking Body Worn Camera Activation with Complaints: The Promise of Metadata.&amp;rdquo; Australian &amp;amp; New Zealand Journal of Criminology, December, 0004865820976190. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0004865820976190&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0004865820976190&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel, John D., and William G. Resh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bureaucratic Discretion, Client Demographics, and Representative Bureaucracy.&amp;rdquo; The American Review of Public Administration 45 (3): 281&amp;ndash;310. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0275074013492008&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0275074013492008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastrofski, Stephen D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Controlling Street-Level Police Discretion.&amp;rdquo; Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science 593 (1): 100&amp;ndash;118.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastrofski, Stephen D., R. Richard Ritti, and Debra Hoffmaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Organizational Determinants of Police Discretion: The Case of Drinking-Driving.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Criminal Justice 15 (5): 387&amp;ndash;402.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastrofski, Stephen D., R. Richard Ritti, and Jeffrey B. Snipes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Expectancy Theory and Police Productivity in DUI Enforcement.&amp;rdquo; Law and Society Review, 113&amp;ndash;148.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maynard-Moody, Steven, and Michael Musheno.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;State Agent or Citizen Agent: Two Narratives of Discretion.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory 10 (2): 329&amp;ndash;358.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social Equities and Inequities in Practice: Street-Level Workers as Agents and Pragmatists.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review 72 (s1): S16&amp;ndash;S23.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maynard-Moody, Steven Williams, Michael Musheno, and Michael Craig Musheno.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cops, Teachers, Counselors: Stories from the Front Lines of Public Service. University of Michigan Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meyers, Allan R., Timothy Heeren, and Ralph Hingson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Discretionary Leniency in Police Enforcement of Laws against Drinking and Driving: Two Examples from the State of Maine, USA.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Criminal Justice 17 (3): 179&amp;ndash;186.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miller, Gary J.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Political Evolution of Principal-Agent Models.&amp;rdquo; Annu. Rev. Polit. Sci. 8: 203&amp;ndash;225. Miller, Lindsay, and Jessica Toliver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Implementing a Body-Worn Camera Program.&amp;rdquo; Washington, D.C.: Police Executive Research Forum. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.justice.gov/iso/opa/resources/472014912134715246869.pdf&#34;&gt;https://www.justice.gov/iso/opa/resources/472014912134715246869.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mourtgos, Scott M., and Ian T. Adams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Assessing Public Perceptions of Police Use-of-Force: Legal Reasonableness and Community Standards.&amp;rdquo; Justice Quarterly 37 (5): 869&amp;ndash;99. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/07418825.2019.1679864&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/07418825.2019.1679864&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mummolo, Jonathan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Modern Police Tactics, Police-Citizen Interactions, and the Prospects for Reform.&amp;rdquo; The Journal of Politics 80 (1): 1&amp;ndash;15. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1086/694393&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1086/694393&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newell, Bryce, and Ruben Greidanus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Officer Discretion and the Choice to Record: Officer Attitudes Towards Body-Worn Camera Activation.&amp;rdquo; North Carolina Law Review 96: 1&amp;ndash;44.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nix, Justin, Justin T. Pickett, Hyunin Baek, and Geoffrey P. Alpert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police Research, Officer Surveys, and Response Rates.&amp;rdquo; Policing and Society 29 (5): 530&amp;ndash;50. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/10439463.2017.1394300&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/10439463.2017.1394300&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nix, Justin, Natalie Todak, and Brandon Tregle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Understanding Body-Worn Camera Diffusion in U.S. Policing.&amp;rdquo; Police Quarterly, April, 1098611120917937. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1098611120917937&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1098611120917937&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owens, Catherine, and William Finn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Body-Worn Video through the Lens of a Cluster Randomized Controlled Trial in London: Implications for Future Research.&amp;rdquo; Policing: A Journal of Policy and Practice 12 (1): 77&amp;ndash;82.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paoline, Eugene A., and William Terrill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police Education, Experience, and the Use of Force.&amp;rdquo; Criminal Justice and Behavior 34 (2): 179&amp;ndash;96.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pelfrey, William V. Jr., and Steven Keener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police Body Worn Cameras: A Mixed Method Approach Assessing Perceptions of Efficacy.&amp;rdquo; Policing: An International Journal of Police Strategies &amp;amp; Management 39 (3): 491&amp;ndash;506.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peterson, Bryce Elling, and Daniel S. Lawrence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Body Cameras and Policing.&amp;rdquo; In Oxford Research Encyclopedia of Criminology and Criminal Justice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President&amp;rsquo;s Task Force on 21st Century Policing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Final Report of the President&amp;rsquo;s Task Force on 21st Century Policing.&amp;rdquo; Washington, DC: Office of Community Oriented Policing Services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rohr, John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethics for Bureaucrats : An Essay on Law and Values, Second Edition. Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1201/9780203756539&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1201/9780203756539&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schaible, Lonnie M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Impact of the Police Professional Identity on Burnout.&amp;rdquo; Policing: An International Journal of Police Strategies &amp;amp; Management 41 (1): 129&amp;ndash;143. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1108/PIJPSM-03-2016-0047&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1108/PIJPSM-03-2016-0047&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shane, Jon M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What Every Chief Executive Should Know: Using Data to Measure Police Performance. Flushing, NY: Looseleaf Law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stress Inside Police Departments. New York: Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780429297229&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780429297229&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shanks, Adam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Video Gives Glimpse of Police Tactics at Clinic.&amp;rdquo; Spokesman-Review, February 18, 2020, sec. Northwest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon, Herbert A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Decision-Making and Administrative Organization.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review 4 (1): 16&amp;ndash;30. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/972435&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/972435&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith, Douglas A., and Jody R. Klein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police Agency Characteristics and Arrest Decisions.&amp;rdquo; Evaluating Performance of Criminal Justice Agencies 19: 63&amp;ndash;98.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snyder, Jamie A., Matthew S. Crow, and John Ortiz Smykla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police Officer and Supervisor Perceptions of Body-Worn Cameras Pre- and Postimplementation: The Importance of Officer Buy-In.&amp;rdquo; Criminal Justice Review, May, 0734016819846223. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0734016819846223&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0734016819846223&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sowa, Jessica E., and Sally Coleman Selden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Administrative Discretion and Active Representation: An Expansion of the Theory of Representative Bureaucracy.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review 63 (6): 700&amp;ndash;710. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/1540-6210.00333&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/1540-6210.00333&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spence, David B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Agency Discretion and the Dynamics of Procedural Reform.&amp;rdquo; Public Administration Review 59 (5): 425&amp;ndash;42. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/977425&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/977425&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stith, Sandra M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police Response to Domestic Violence: The Influence of Individual and Familial Factors.&amp;rdquo; Violence and Victims 5 (1): 37.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sutherland, Alex, Barak Ariel, William Farrar, and Randy De Anda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Post-Experimental Follow-Ups&amp;mdash;Fade-out versus Persistence Effects: The Rialto Police Body-Worn Camera Experiment Four Years On.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Criminal Justice 53: 110&amp;ndash;116.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrill, William, and Stephen D. Mastrofski.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Situational and Officer-Based Determinants of Police Coercion.&amp;rdquo; Justice Quarterly 19 (2): 215&amp;ndash;48.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todak, Natalie, and Janne E. Gaub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Predictors of Police Body-Worn Camera Acceptance: Digging Deeper into Officers&#39; Perceptions.&amp;rdquo; Policing: An International Journal ahead-of-print (ahead-of-print). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1108/PIJPSM-06-2019-0085&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1108/PIJPSM-06-2019-0085&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tummers, Lars, and Victor Bekkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Policy Implementation, Street-Level Bureaucracy, and the Importance of Discretion.&amp;rdquo; Public Management Review 16 (4): 527&amp;ndash;547.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. Census Bureau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Population.&amp;rdquo; US Population Statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.census.gov/topics/population.html&#34;&gt;https://www.census.gov/topics/population.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walker, Samuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police Accountability and the Central Problem in American Criminal Justice.&amp;rdquo; In Holding Police Accountable, 1&amp;ndash;25. Washington, DC: The Urban Institute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallace, Danielle, Michael D. White, Janne E. Gaub, and Natalie Todak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Body-Worn Cameras as a Potential Source of Depolicing: Testing for Camera-Induced Passivity.&amp;rdquo; Criminology 56 (3): 481&amp;ndash;509.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White, Michael D., and Aili Malm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cops, Cameras, and Crisis: The Potential and the Perils of Police Body-Worn Cameras. NYU Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White, Michael D., Natalie Todak, and Janne E. Gaub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Examining Body-Worn Camera Integration and Acceptance among Police Officers, Citizens, and External Stakeholders.&amp;rdquo; Criminology &amp;amp; Public Policy 17 (3): 649&amp;ndash;677.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilson, James Q.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Varieties of Police Behavior: The Management of Law and Order in Eight Communities. Cambridge, MA: Harvard Univ. Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yokum, David, Anita Ravishankar, and Alexander Coppock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A Randomized Control Trial Evaluating the Effects of Police Body-Worn Cameras.&amp;rdquo; Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 116 (21): 10329&amp;ndash;10332.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young, Jacob TN, and Justin T. Ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A Longitudinal Analysis of the Relationship between Administrative Policy, Technological Preferences, and Body-Worn Camera Activation among Police Officers.&amp;rdquo; Policing: A Journal of Policy and Practice 12 (1): 27&amp;ndash;42.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corresponding author: Ian Adams, University of Utah, ian.adams@utah.edu &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian T. Adams (corresponding author) is a Ph.D. candidate in the Department of Political Science at the University of Utah. His research focuses on body-worn cameras, police officers, and emotional labor. Ian is a 2018 American Society of Public Administration Founders&#39; Fellow, and a 2021 doctoral fellow of the Academy of Criminal Justice Sciences. More information on his research is available at &lt;a href=&#34;www.ianadamsresearch.com&#34;&gt;www.ianadamsresearch.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Mourtgos is a Ph.D. student in the Department of Political Science at the University of Utah. His research focuses on policing and criminal justice policy. Scott is a 2020 National Institute of Justice LEADS Scholar. More information on his research is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://smourtgos.netlify.app/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;https://smourtgos.netlify.app/&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharon Mastracci is a Professor of Political Science and the Director of the Programs of Public Affairs at the University of Utah.She studies gender in public organizations and emotional labor and dirty work in public service. She was a 2014-2015 Fulbright scholar to the United Kingdom and a 2020 Fellow of the National Academy of Public Administration. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contrasting emotional labor and burnout in civilian and sworn law enforcement personnel</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2020-01-01_contrasting_emotiona/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2020-01-01_contrasting_emotiona/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Labor in Emergency Dispatch: Gauging Effects of Training Protocols</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2020-01-01_emotional_labor_in_e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2020-01-01_emotional_labor_in_e/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s not depersonalization, It&#39;s emotional labor: Examining surface acting and use-of-force with evidence from the US</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2020-01-01_its_not_depersonali/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2020-01-01_its_not_depersonali/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andrew G. Ferguson, The Rise of Big Data Policing: Surveillance, Race, and the Future of Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_andrew_g._ferguson_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_andrew_g._ferguson_/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Public Perceptions of Police Use-of-Force: Legal Reasonableness and Community Standards</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_assessing_public_per/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_assessing_public_per/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional labour in non-governmental organisations: narrative analysis and theory expansion</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_emotional_labour_in_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_emotional_labour_in_/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Values Shape Program Perceptions: The “Organic Ethos” and Producers’ Assessments of U.S. Organic Policy Impacts</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_how_values_shape_pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_how_values_shape_pro/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Emotional Labor Easier in Collectivist or Individualist Cultures? An East–West Comparison</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_is_emotional_labor_e/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_is_emotional_labor_e/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Body Worn Cameras Effects on Officers Burnout and Perceived Organizational Support</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/police-body-worn-cameras-effects-on-officers-burnout-and-perceived-organizational-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/police-body-worn-cameras-effects-on-officers-burnout-and-perceived-organizational-support/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/police-body-worn-cameras-effects-on-officers-burnout-and-perceived-organizational-support/index_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ianadamsresearch.com/pdfs/bwc-burnout.pdf&#34;&gt;Download file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;bibtex-citation&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BibTeX citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bibtex&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; @article{Adams_Mastracci_2019, title={Police Body-Worn Cameras: Effects on Officers’ Burnout and Perceived Organizational Support}, volume={22}, DOI={https://doi.org/10.1177/1098611118783987}, abstractNote={Police departments in the United States are rapidly adopting body-worn cameras (BWCs). To date, no study has investigated the effects of BWCs on police officers themselves, despite evidence suggesting negative effects of electronic performance monitoring on employee well-being. Police officers already experience higher levels of burnout than other professions. We hypothesize that the intense surveillance of BWCs will manifest in how police officers perceive the organizational support of their departments and will increase burnout. We test these hypotheses using data from patrol officers (n=271) and structural equation modeling. We find BWCs increase police officer burnout, and this effect is statistically different from zero. We also find that BWCs decrease officers’ perceived organizational support, which mediates the relationship between BWCs and burnout. Greater perceived organizational support can blunt the negative effects of BWCs. Our study is the first to situate effects on officers at the center of BWC literature.}, number={1}, journal={Police Quarterly}, author={Adams, Ian T. and Mastracci, Sharon H.}, year={2019}, pages={5–30} }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Prosecutorial Actions on Deterrence: A County-Level Analysis:</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_the_effect_of_prosec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_the_effect_of_prosec/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rhetoric of de-policing: Evaluating open-ended survey responses from police officers with machine learning-based structural topic modeling</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_the_rhetoric_of_de-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_the_rhetoric_of_de-p/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UK</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_the_uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_the_uk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trending Interconnectedness: The Value of Comparative Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_trending_interconnec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_trending_interconnec/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Emotional Labor at the Cultural Level</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_understanding_emotio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2019-01-01_understanding_emotio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“That’s What the Money’s for”: Alienation and Emotional Labor in Public Service</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2018-01-01_thats-what-the-moneys-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2018-01-01_thats-what-the-moneys-for/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visibility is a Trap: The Ethics of Police Body-Worn Cameras and Control</title>
      <link>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2017-01-01_visibility_is_a_trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ianadamsresearch.com/publication/2017-01-01_visibility_is_a_trap/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
